<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conformity on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1326/tags/conformity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conformity on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1326/tags/conformity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Think for Yourself</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/think/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/think/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/think/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-think-for-yourself&#34;&gt;How to Think for Yourself&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some kinds of work that you can&amp;rsquo;t do well without thinking differently from your peers. To be a successful scientist, for example, it&amp;rsquo;s not enough just to be correct. Your ideas have to be both correct and novel. You can&amp;rsquo;t publish papers saying things other people already know. You need to say things no one else has realized yet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The same is true for investors. It&amp;rsquo;s not enough for a public market investor to predict correctly how a company will do. If a lot of other people make the same prediction, the stock price will already reflect it, and there&amp;rsquo;s no room to make money. The only valuable insights are the ones most other investors don&amp;rsquo;t share.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orthodox Privilege</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/orth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/orth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;orthodox-privilege&#34;&gt;Orthodox Privilege&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Few people are capable of expressing with equanimity opinions which differ from the prejudices of their social environment. Most people are even incapable of forming such opinions.&amp;quot;— Einstein&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of talk about privilege lately. Although the concept is overused, there is something to it, and in particular to the idea that privilege makes you blind — that you can&amp;rsquo;t see things that are visible to someone whose life is very different from yours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What You Can&#39;t Say</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/say/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/say/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/say/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-you-cant-say&#34;&gt;What You Can&amp;rsquo;t Say&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever seen an old photo of yourself and been embarrassed at the way you looked? Did we actually dress like that? We did. And we had no idea how silly we looked. It&amp;rsquo;s the nature of fashion to be invisible, in the same way the movement of the earth is invisible to all of us riding on it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What scares me is that there are moral fashions too. They&amp;rsquo;re just as arbitrary, and just as invisible to most people. But they&amp;rsquo;re much more dangerous. Fashion is mistaken for good design; moral fashion is mistaken for good. Dressing oddly gets you laughed at. Violating moral fashions can get you fired, ostracized, imprisoned, or even killed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
