<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Investors on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1366/tags/investors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Investors on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1366/tags/investors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Fundraising Survival Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/fundraising/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/fundraising/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/fundraising/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-fundraising-survival-guide&#34;&gt;A Fundraising Survival Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Raising money is the second hardest part of starting a startup. The hardest part is making something people want: most startups that die, die because they didn&amp;rsquo;t do that. But the second biggest cause of death is probably the difficulty of raising money. Fundraising is brutal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One reason it&amp;rsquo;s so brutal is simply the brutality of markets. People who&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of their lives in schools or big companies may not have been exposed to that. Professors and bosses usually feel some sense of responsibility toward you; if you make a valiant effort and fail, they&amp;rsquo;ll cut you a break. Markets are less forgiving. Customers don&amp;rsquo;t care how hard you worked, only whether you solved their problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring is Obsolete</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/hiring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/hiring/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;hiring-is-obsolete&#34;&gt;Hiring is Obsolete&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at the Berkeley CSUA.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The three big powers on the Internet now are Yahoo, Google, and Microsoft. Average age of their founders: 24. So it is pretty well established now that grad students can start successful companies. And if grad students can do it, why not undergrads?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like everything else in technology, the cost of starting a startup has decreased dramatically. Now it&amp;rsquo;s so low that it has disappeared into the noise. The main cost of starting a Web-based startup is food and rent. Which means it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost much more to start a company than to be a total slacker. You can probably start a startup on ten thousand dollars of seed funding, if you&amp;rsquo;re prepared to live on ramen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Be Silicon Valley</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/siliconvalley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/siliconvalley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/siliconvalley/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-be-silicon-valley&#34;&gt;How to Be Silicon Valley&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a keynote at Xtech.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Could you reproduce Silicon Valley elsewhere, or is there something unique about it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprising if it were hard to reproduce in other countries, because you couldn&amp;rsquo;t reproduce it in most of the US either. What does it take to make a silicon valley even here?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What it takes is the right people. If you could get the right ten thousand people to move from Silicon Valley to Buffalo, Buffalo would become Silicon Valley. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Convince Investors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/convince/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/convince/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/convince/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-convince-investors&#34;&gt;How to Convince Investors&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2013&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When people hurt themselves lifting heavy things, it&amp;rsquo;s usually because they try to lift with their back. The right way to lift heavy things is to let your legs do the work. Inexperienced founders make the same mistake when trying to convince investors. They try to convince with their pitch. Most would be better off if they let their startup do the work—if they started by understanding why their startup is worth investing in, then simply explained this well to investors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Pittsburgh a Startup Hub</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/pgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/pgh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/pgh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-make-pittsburgh-a-startup-hub&#34;&gt;How to Make Pittsburgh a Startup Hub&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2016&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This is a talk I gave at an event called Opt412 in Pittsburgh. Much of it will apply to other towns. But not all, because as I say in the talk, Pittsburgh has some important advantages over most would-be startup hubs.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What would it take to make Pittsburgh into a startup hub, like Silicon Valley? I understand Pittsburgh pretty well, because I grew up here, in Monroeville. And I understand Silicon Valley pretty well because that&amp;rsquo;s where I live now. Could you get that kind of startup ecosystem going here?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Present to Investors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/investors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/investors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/investors/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-present-to-investors&#34;&gt;How to Present to Investors&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a few days it will be Demo Day, when the startups we funded this summer present to investors. Y Combinator funds startups twice a year, in January and June. Ten weeks later we invite all the investors we know to hear them present what they&amp;rsquo;ve built so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ten weeks is not much time. The average startup probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much to show for itself after ten weeks. But the average startup fails. When you look at the ones that went on to do great things, you find a lot that began with someone pounding out a prototype in a week or two of nonstop work. Startups are a counterexample to the rule that haste makes waste.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Raise Money</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/fr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/fr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/fr/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-raise-money&#34;&gt;How to Raise Money&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2013&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most startups that raise money do it more than once. A typical trajectory might be (1) to get started with a few tens of thousands from something like Y Combinator or individual angels, then (2) raise a few hundred thousand to a few million to build the company, and then (3) once the company is clearly succeeding, raise one or more later rounds to accelerate growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investor Herd Dynamics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/herd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/herd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/herd/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;investor-herd-dynamics&#34;&gt;Investor Herd Dynamics&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2013&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest component in most investors&amp;rsquo; opinion of you is the opinion of other investors. Which is of course a recipe for exponential growth. When one investor wants to invest in you, that makes other investors want to, which makes others want to, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes inexperienced founders mistakenly conclude that manipulating these forces is the essence of fundraising. They hear stories about stampedes to invest in successful startups, and think it&amp;rsquo;s therefore the mark of a successful startup to have this happen. But actually the two are not that highly correlated. Lots of startups that cause stampedes end up flaming out (in extreme cases, partly as a result of the stampede), and lots of very successful startups were only moderately popular with investors the first time they raised money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Equity Equation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/equity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/equity/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-equity-equation&#34;&gt;The Equity Equation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An investor wants to give you money for a certain percentage of your startup. Should you take it? You&amp;rsquo;re about to hire your first employee. How much stock should you give him?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are some of the hardest questions founders face. And yet both have the same answer:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1/(1 - n)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whenever you&amp;rsquo;re trading stock in your company for anything, whether it&amp;rsquo;s money or an employee or a deal with another company, the test for whether to do it is the same. You should give up n% of your company if what you trade it for improves your average outcome enough that the (100 - n)% you have left is worth more than the whole company was before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hacker&#39;s Guide to Investors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/guidetoinvestors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/guidetoinvestors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/guidetoinvestors/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-hackers-guide-to-investors&#34;&gt;The Hacker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Investors&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a keynote talk at the 2007 ASES Summit at Stanford.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The world of investors is a foreign one to most hackers—partly because investors are so unlike hackers, and partly because they tend to operate in secret. I&amp;rsquo;ve been dealing with this world for many years, both as a founder and an investor, and I still don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ronco Principle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/ronco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/ronco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/ronco/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-ronco-principle&#34;&gt;The Ronco Principle&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2015&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No one, VC or angel, has invested in more of the top startups than Ron Conway. He knows what happened in every deal in the Valley, half the time because he arranged it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And yet he&amp;rsquo;s a super nice guy. In fact, nice is not the word. Ronco is good. I know of zero instances in which he has behaved badly. It&amp;rsquo;s hard even to imagine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
