<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algebraic-Geometry on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/algebraic-geometry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algebraic-Geometry on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/algebraic-geometry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>For potential Ph.D. students</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/for-potential-phd-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/for-potential-phd-students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/for-potential-phd-students.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://math.stanford.edu/~vakil/potentialstudents.html&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-potential-phd-students&#34;&gt;For potential Ph.D. students&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the next few years, I may take on a few additional Ph.D. students, although times may come when I&amp;rsquo;ll be too full (e.g. a time that ended recently). This page is intended for those considering working with me, although it also contains some tips for graduate students in general, as well as an idea of what I expect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Algebraic geometry (or at least my take on it) is a technical subject that also requires a good deal of background in other subjects, as well as geometric intuition. So &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; I take you on as a new student, you should be comfortable with the foundations of the subject, which means having done the majority of the exercises in Hartshorne or my course notes, and being able to explain them on demand. (You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do this on your own; I&amp;rsquo;m happy talking with you through this process.) You should also be actively interested in learning about nearby subjects that interest you. Which subjects they are is up to you. If you&amp;rsquo;re not interested in regularly attending talks, and being broadly interested in mathematics outside of your thesis topic, or if you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like getting technical in a rather serious way, I&amp;rsquo;m probably not a good fit for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
