<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economy on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1366/tags/economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economy on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1366/tags/economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Founder Visa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/foundervisa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/foundervisa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/foundervisa/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-founder-visa&#34;&gt;The Founder Visa&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I usually avoid politics, but since we now seem to have an administration that&amp;rsquo;s open to suggestions, I&amp;rsquo;m going to risk making one. The single biggest thing the government could do to increase the number of startups in this country is a policy that would cost nothing: establish a new class of visa for startup founders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest constraint on the number of new startups that get created in the US is not tax policy or employment law or even Sarbanes-Oxley. It&amp;rsquo;s that we won&amp;rsquo;t let the people who want to start them into the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Refragmentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/re/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/re/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/re/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-refragmentation&#34;&gt;The Refragmentation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2016&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One advantage of being old is that you can see change happen in your lifetime. A lot of the change I&amp;rsquo;ve seen is fragmentation. US politics is much more polarized than it used to be. Culturally we have ever less common ground. The creative class flocks to a handful of happy cities, abandoning the rest. And increasing economic inequality means the spread between rich and poor is growing too. I&amp;rsquo;d like to propose a hypothesis: that all these trends are instances of the same phenomenon. And moreover, that the cause is not some force that&amp;rsquo;s pulling us apart, but rather the erosion of forces that had been pushing us together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the Bubble Got Right</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/bubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/bubble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/bubble/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-the-bubble-got-right&#34;&gt;What the Bubble Got Right&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from an invited talk at ICFP 2004.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had a front row seat for the Internet Bubble, because I worked at Yahoo during 1998 and 1999. One day, when the stock was trading around $200, I sat down and calculated what I thought the price should be. The answer I got was $12. I went to the next cubicle and told my friend Trevor. &amp;ldquo;Twelve!&amp;rdquo; he said. He tried to sound indignant, but he didn&amp;rsquo;t quite manage it. He knew as well as I did that our valuation was crazy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why to Start a Startup in a Bad Economy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/badeconomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/badeconomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/badeconomy/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-to-start-a-startup-in-a-bad-economy&#34;&gt;Why to Start a Startup in a Bad Economy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The economic situation is apparently so grim that some experts fear we may be in for a stretch as bad as the mid seventies. When Microsoft and Apple were founded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As those examples suggest, a recession may not be such a bad time to start a startup. I&amp;rsquo;m not claiming it&amp;rsquo;s a particularly good time either. The truth is more boring: the state of the economy doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter much either way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
