<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conclusion on Linguista</title><link>https://linguista.cn/tags/conclusion/</link><description>Recent content in Conclusion on Linguista</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>zh-cn</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://linguista.cn/tags/conclusion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>结语</title><link>https://linguista.cn/courses/agent-skills-with-anthropic/10.-conclusion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://linguista.cn/courses/agent-skills-with-anthropic/10.-conclusion/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="结语"&gt;结语&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="摘要"&gt;摘要&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本课程总结了创建和使用 Claude 智能体技能的核心要点。重点介绍了从基础 Markdown 指令开始，通过逐步披露原则进行扩展的开发方法，强调了在实际场景中监控和迭代的重要性。同时提醒开发者充分利用 Claude 对技能的理解，通过对话开始创建过程，并使用技能创建器遵循最佳实践。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="要点"&gt;要点&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;从基本 Markdown 指令开始，遵循逐步披露原则进行扩展&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在真实场景中监控智能体如何使用技能，并根据观察结果迭代&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;确保技能描述包含足够细节，使智能体知道何时调用&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;利用 Claude 对技能的深入理解，通过对话开始创建过程&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;使用技能创建器（Skill Creator）技能来遵循最佳实践&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;视频信息：&lt;a href="https://learn.deeplearning.ai/courses/agent-skills-with-anthropic/lesson/dea3n4/conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="中文翻译"&gt;中文翻译&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;恭喜你坚持到了这里。你已经学会了如何创建技能，探索了它们的最佳实践，并看到了它们在不同平台上的实际应用。在创建技能时，从基本的 Markdown 指令开始，然后遵循逐步披露（Progressive Disclosure）的原则进行扩展。监控你的智能体在真实场景中如何使用你的技能，并根据观察结果进行迭代。确保描述包含足够的细节，以便你的智能体知道何时使用它。别忘了，Claude 对什么是技能非常了解。因此，你总是可以通过一个简单的对话开始创建技能，然后使用技能创建器（Skill Creator）技能来遵循最佳实践。感谢你加入我的这段旅程。我迫不及待地想看到你用智能体技能构建出什么。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="english-script"&gt;English Script&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on making it this far. You&amp;rsquo;ve learned how to create skills, explored their best practices, and seen them in action across different platforms. When creating a skill, start with basic markdown instructions, then expand later following progressive disclosure. Monitor how your agent uses your skill in real scenarios and iterate based on observations. Make sure the description contains enough detail for your agent to know when to use it. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget, Claude is very knowledgeable about what skills are. So you can always start with a simple conversation to begin creating skills and then use the skill creator skill to follow best practices. Thank you for joining me in this journey. And I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what you build with agent skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>