<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1326/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1326/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Founder Mode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/foundermode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/foundermode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/foundermode/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;founder-mode&#34;&gt;Founder Mode&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At a YC event last week Brian Chesky gave a talk that everyone who was there will remember. Most founders I talked to afterward said it was the best they&amp;rsquo;d ever heard. Ron Conway, for the first time in his life, forgot to take notes. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to try to reproduce it here. Instead I want to talk about a question it raised.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theme of Brian&amp;rsquo;s talk was that the conventional wisdom about how to run larger companies is mistaken. As Airbnb grew, well-meaning people advised him that he had to run the company in a certain way for it to scale. Their advice could be optimistically summarized as &amp;ldquo;hire good people and give them room to do their jobs.&amp;rdquo; He followed this advice and the results were disastrous. So he had to figure out a better way on his own, which he did partly by studying how Steve Jobs ran Apple. So far it seems to be working. Airbnb&amp;rsquo;s free cash flow margin is now among the best in Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jessica Livingston</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/jessica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/jessica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/jessica/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;jessica-livingston&#34;&gt;Jessica Livingston&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2015&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few months ago an article about Y Combinator said that early on it had been a &amp;ldquo;one-man show.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s sadly common to read that sort of thing. But the problem with that description is not just that it&amp;rsquo;s unfair. It&amp;rsquo;s also misleading. Much of what&amp;rsquo;s most novel about YC is due to Jessica Livingston. If you don&amp;rsquo;t understand her, you don&amp;rsquo;t understand YC. So let me tell you a little about Jessica.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mean</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/mean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/mean/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;mean&#34;&gt;Mean&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It struck me recently how few of the most successful people I know are mean. There are exceptions, but remarkably few.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanness isn&amp;rsquo;t rare. In fact, one of the things the internet has shown us is how mean people can be. A few decades ago, only famous people and professional writers got to publish their opinions. Now everyone can, and we can all see the long tail of meanness that had previously been hidden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/pow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/pow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/pow/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;pow&#34;&gt;Pow&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2017&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People who are powerful but uncharismatic will tend to be disliked. Their power makes them a target for criticism that they don&amp;rsquo;t have the charisma to disarm. That was Hillary Clinton&amp;rsquo;s problem. It also tends to be a problem for any CEO who is more of a builder than a schmoozer. And yet the builder-type CEO is (like Hillary) probably the best person for the job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
