<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Society on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1366/tags/society/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Society on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1366/tags/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Addiction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/addiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/addiction/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;addiction&#34;&gt;Addiction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Acceleration of Addictiveness July 2010&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What hard liquor, cigarettes, heroin, and crack have in common is that they&amp;rsquo;re all more concentrated forms of less addictive predecessors. Most if not all the things we describe as addictive are. And the scary thing is, the process that created them is accelerating.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to stop it. It&amp;rsquo;s the same process that cures diseases: technological progress. Technological progress means making things do more of what we want. When the thing we want is something we want to want, we consider technological progress good. If some new technique makes solar cells x% more efficient, that seems strictly better. When progress concentrates something we don&amp;rsquo;t want to want — when it transforms opium into heroin — it seems bad. But it&amp;rsquo;s the same process at work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After Credentials</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/credentials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/credentials/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;after-credentials&#34;&gt;After Credentials&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I read a New York Times article on South Korean cram schools that said Admission to the right university can make or break an ambitious young South Korean. A parent added: &amp;ldquo;In our country, college entrance exams determine 70 to 80 percent of a person&amp;rsquo;s future.&amp;rdquo; It was striking how old fashioned this sounded. And yet when I was in high school it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have seemed too far off as a description of the US. Which means things must have been changing here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bradley&#39;s Ghost</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/polls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/polls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/polls/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;bradleys-ghost&#34;&gt;Bradley&amp;rsquo;s Ghost&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of people are writing now about why Kerry lost. Here I want to examine a more specific question: why were the exit polls so wrong?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Ohio, which Kerry ultimately lost 49-51, exit polls gave him a 52-48 victory. And this wasn&amp;rsquo;t just random error. In every swing state they overestimated the Kerry vote. In Florida, which Bush ultimately won 52-47, exit polls predicted a dead heat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conformism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/conformism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/conformism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/conformism/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;conformism&#34;&gt;Conformism&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-four-quadrants-of-conformism&#34;&gt;The Four Quadrants of Conformism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most revealing ways to classify people is by the degree and aggressiveness of their conformism. Imagine a Cartesian coordinate system whose horizontal axis runs from conventional-minded on the left to independent-minded on the right, and whose vertical axis runs from passive at the bottom to aggressive at the top. The resulting four quadrants define four types of people. Starting in the upper left and going counter-clockwise: aggressively conventional-minded, passively conventional-minded, passively independent-minded, and aggressively independent-minded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lies We Tell Kids</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/lies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/lies/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;lies-we-tell-kids&#34;&gt;Lies We Tell Kids&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adults lie constantly to kids. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying we should stop, but I think we should at least examine which lies we tell and why.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There may also be a benefit to us. We were all lied to as kids, and some of the lies we were told still affect us. So by studying the ways adults lie to kids, we may be able to clear our heads of lies we were told.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Gap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/gap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/gap/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;mind-the-gap&#34;&gt;Mind the Gap&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When people care enough about something to do it well, those who do it best tend to be far better than everyone else. There&amp;rsquo;s a huge gap between Leonardo and second-rate contemporaries like Borgognone. You see the same gap between Raymond Chandler and the average writer of detective novels. A top-ranked professional chess player could play ten thousand games against an ordinary club player without losing once.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The High-Res Society</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/highres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/highres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/highres/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-high-res-society&#34;&gt;The High-Res Society&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For nearly all of history the success of a society was proportionate to its ability to assemble large and disciplined organizations. Those who bet on economies of scale generally won, which meant the largest organizations were the most successful ones.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Things have already changed so much that this is hard for us to believe, but till just a few decades ago the largest organizations tended to be the most progressive. An ambitious kid graduating from college in 1960 wanted to work in the huge, gleaming offices of Ford, or General Electric, or NASA. Small meant small-time. Small in 1960 didn&amp;rsquo;t mean a cool little startup. It meant uncle Sid&amp;rsquo;s shoe store.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Origins of Wokeness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/woke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/woke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/woke/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-origins-of-wokeness&#34;&gt;The Origins of Wokeness&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;prig&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t very common now, but if you look up the definition, it will sound familiar. Google&amp;rsquo;s isn&amp;rsquo;t bad: A self-righteously moralistic person who behaves as if superior to others. This sense of the word originated in the 18th century, and its age is an important clue: it shows that although wokeness is a comparatively recent phenomenon, it&amp;rsquo;s an instance of a much older one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Real Reason to End the Death Penalty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/real/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/real/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/real/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-real-reason-to-end-the-death-penalty&#34;&gt;The Real Reason to End the Death Penalty&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When intellectuals talk about the death penalty, they talk about things like whether it&amp;rsquo;s permissible for the state to take someone&amp;rsquo;s life, whether the death penalty acts as a deterrent, and whether more death sentences are given to some groups than others. But in practice the debate about the death penalty is not about whether it&amp;rsquo;s ok to kill murderers. It&amp;rsquo;s about whether it&amp;rsquo;s ok to kill innocent people, because at least 4% of people on death row are innocent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Refragmentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/re/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/re/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/re/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-refragmentation&#34;&gt;The Refragmentation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2016&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One advantage of being old is that you can see change happen in your lifetime. A lot of the change I&amp;rsquo;ve seen is fragmentation. US politics is much more polarized than it used to be. Culturally we have ever less common ground. The creative class flocks to a handful of happy cities, abandoning the rest. And increasing economic inequality means the spread between rich and poor is growing too. I&amp;rsquo;d like to propose a hypothesis: that all these trends are instances of the same phenomenon. And moreover, that the cause is not some force that&amp;rsquo;s pulling us apart, but rather the erosion of forces that had been pushing us together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
