<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathematics on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/categories/mathematics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mathematics on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 16:44:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/categories/mathematics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On the importance of partial progress</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/on-the-importance-of-partial-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 16:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/on-the-importance-of-partial-progress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/on-the-importance-of-partial-progress.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/on-the-importance-of-partial-progress/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-the-importance-of-partial-progress&#34;&gt;On the importance of partial progress&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Initially posted on Google+ on July 17, 2012. -T]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the secrets to mathematical problem solving is that one needs to place a high value on partial progress, as being a crucial stepping stone to fully solving the problem. This can be a rather different mindset than what one commonly sees in more &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; situations such as business, sports, engineering, or politics, where actual success or failure often matters much more than what one can salvage from a partial success. I think the basic reason for this is that in the purely theoretical world of mathematics, there is basically a zero cost in taking an argument that partially solves a problem, and then combining it with other ideas to make a complete solution; but in the real world, it can be difficult, costly, or socially unacceptable to reuse or recycle anything that is (or is perceived to be) even a partial failure. Software engineering is one of the few exceptions to this general rule, as it is almost as easy to reuse software code as it is to reuse a mathematical argument.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Timeline of postdoc applications | Lovely little lemmas</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/timeline-of-postdoc-applications-lovely-little-lemmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 03:07:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/timeline-of-postdoc-applications-lovely-little-lemmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/timeline-of-postdoc-applications-lovely-little-lemmas.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lovelylittlelemmas.rjprojects.net/timeline-of-postdoc-applications/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;timeline-of-postdoc-applications--lovely-little-lemmas&#34;&gt;Timeline of postdoc applications | Lovely little lemmas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Posted on 18 April 2018 by Remy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an attempt to give a rough outline of the timeline of the last year of a PhD in mathematics, especially with the eye on applying for US postdocs through MathJobs. I will say a few words about European postdocs as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the type of information I wish I had available before I started the process, so I&amp;rsquo;m hoping it may be of help to some people. I take full responsibility for all inaccuracies; but if you do find that this information is incorrect or incomplete, let me know in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are some useful, but little-known, features of the tools used in professional mathematics?</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/what-are-some-useful-but-little-known-features-of-the-tools-used-in-professional-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/what-are-some-useful-but-little-known-features-of-the-tools-used-in-professional-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/what-are-some-useful-but-little-known-features-of-the-tools-used-in-professional-mathematics.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/2017/07/07/what-are-some-useful-but-little-known-features-of-the-tools-used-in-professional-mathematics/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-are-some-useful-but-little-known-features-of-the-tools-used-in-professional-mathematics&#34;&gt;What are some useful, but little-known, features of the tools used in professional mathematics?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I was talking with Ed Dunne, who is currently the Executive Editor of Mathematical Reviews (and in particular with its online incarnation at MathSciNet). At the time, I was mentioning how laborious it was for me to create a BibTeX file for dozens of references by using MathSciNet to locate each reference separately, and to export each one to BibTeX format. He then informed me that underneath to every MathSciNet reference there was a little link to add the reference to a Clipboard, and then one could export the entire Clipboard at once to whatever format one wished. In retrospect, this was a functionality of the site that had always been visible, but I had never bothered to explore it, and now I can populate a BibTeX file much more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continually aim just beyond your current range</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/continually-aim-just-beyond-your-current-range/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2007 19:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/continually-aim-just-beyond-your-current-range/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/continually-aim-just-beyond-your-current-range.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/continually-aim-just-beyond-your-current-range/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;continually-aim-just-beyond-your-current-range&#34;&gt;Continually aim just beyond your current range&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A successful individual typically sets his next goal somewhat but not too much above his last achievement. In this way he steadily raises his level of aspiration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kurt Lewin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among chess players, it is generally accepted that one of the most effective ways to improve one&amp;rsquo;s skill is to continually play against opponents which are slightly higher rated than you are. In mathematics, the opponents are unsolved or imperfectly understood mathematical problems, concepts, and theories, rather than other mathematicians; but the principle is broadly the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does one have to be a genius to do maths?</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/does-one-have-to-be-a-genius-to-do-maths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 01:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/does-one-have-to-be-a-genius-to-do-maths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/does-one-have-to-be-a-genius-to-do-maths.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/does-one-have-to-be-a-genius-to-do-maths/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;does-one-have-to-be-a-genius-to-do-maths&#34;&gt;Does one have to be a genius to do maths?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Better beware of notions like genius and inspiration; they are a sort of magic wand and should be used sparingly by anybody who wants to see things clearly.&#xA;(José Ortega y Gasset, &amp;ldquo;Notes on the novel&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does one have to be a genius to do mathematics?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The answer is an emphatic &lt;strong&gt;NO&lt;/strong&gt;. In order to make good and useful contributions to mathematics, one does need to &lt;strong&gt;work hard&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;learn one&amp;rsquo;s field well&lt;/strong&gt;, learn &lt;strong&gt;other fields&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;ask questions&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;talk to other mathematicians&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;think about the &amp;ldquo;big picture&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. And yes, a reasonable amount of intelligence, &lt;strong&gt;patience&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;maturity&lt;/strong&gt; is also required. But one does &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; need some sort of magic &amp;ldquo;genius gene&amp;rdquo; that spontaneously generates &lt;em&gt;ex nihilo&lt;/em&gt; deep insights, unexpected solutions to problems, or other supernatural abilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving mathematical problems</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/solving-mathematical-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 00:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/solving-mathematical-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/solving-mathematical-problems.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/solving-mathematical-problems/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;solving-mathematical-problems&#34;&gt;Solving mathematical problems&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chaque vérité que je trouvois étant une règle qui me servoit après à en trouver d&amp;rsquo;autres [Each truth that I discovered became a rule which then served to discover other truths].&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— René Descartes, &amp;ldquo;Discours de la Méthode&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Problem solving, from homework problems to unsolved problems, is certainly an important aspect of mathematics, though definitely &lt;strong&gt;not the only one&lt;/strong&gt;. Later in your research career, you will find that problems are mainly solved by knowledge (of &lt;strong&gt;your own field&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;of other fields&lt;/strong&gt;), experience, &lt;strong&gt;patience&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;hard work&lt;/strong&gt;; but for the type of problems one sees in school, college or in mathematics competitions one needs a slightly different set of problem solving skills. I do have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/books/&#34;&gt;book on how to solve mathematical problems&lt;/a&gt; at this level; in particular, the &lt;strong&gt;first chapter&lt;/strong&gt; discusses general problem-solving strategies. There are of course several other problem-solving books, such as Polya&amp;rsquo;s classic &amp;ldquo;How to solve it&amp;rdquo;, which I myself learnt from while competing at the Mathematics Olympiads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On writing</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 20:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/on-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/on-writing.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/advice-on-writing-papers/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article is an important one and serves as the main page for the academic writing topic on Terry Tao&amp;rsquo;s blog. There are many links in this article, and the corresponding articles have not been translated on this site yet. Therefore, clicking the links in this article will directly jump to the original article on Terry Tao&amp;rsquo;s blog. Please feel free to check them out!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are three rules for writing the novel. Unfortunately, no one knows what they are.&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/W._Somerset_Maugham&#34;&gt;W. Somerset Maugham&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be considerate of your audience</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/be-considerate-of-your-audience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/be-considerate-of-your-audience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/be-considerate-of-your-audience.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/be-considerate-of-your-audience/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;be-considerate-of-your-audience&#34;&gt;Be considerate of your audience&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think like a wise man, but communicate in the language of the people.&#xA;— William Butler Yeats&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This advice applies primarily to papers, but also to lectures and seminars (though one should also bear in mind that talks are not the same as papers).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, one of the most important things in mathematics (though certainly not the only thing) is to get results, and prove them correctly. However, one also needs to make a good faith effort to communicate these results to their intended audience. (It may feel like you have attained some level of intellectual achievement if you can discuss a topic which is so difficult or jargon-heavy that most of your audience do not understand what you are talking about, but it is in fact a far greater intellectual achievement if you can actually communicate that difficult topic effectively to such an audience.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write down what you’ve done</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/write-down-what-youve-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/write-down-what-youve-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/write-down-what-youve-done.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/write-down-what-youve-done/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;write-down-what-youve-done&#34;&gt;Write down what you’ve done&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every composer knows the anguish and despair occasioned by forgetting ideas which one had no time to write down.&#xA;— Hector Berlioz&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were many occasions early in my career when I read, heard about, or stumbled upon some neat mathematical trick or argument, and thought I understood it well enough that I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to write it down; and then, say six months later, when I actually needed to recall that trick, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t reconstruct it at all. Eventually I resolved to write down (preferably on a computer) a sketch of any interesting argument I came across – not necessarily at a publication level of quality, but detailed enough that I could then safely forget about the details, and readily recover the argument from the sketch whenever the need arises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t prematurely obsess on a single “big problem” or “big theory”</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/dont-prematurely-obsess-on-a-single-big-problem-or-big-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/dont-prematurely-obsess-on-a-single-big-problem-or-big-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/dont-prematurely-obsess-on-a-single-big-problem-or-big-theory.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/dont-prematurely-obsess-on-a-single-big-problem-or-big-theory/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;dont-prematurely-obsess-on-a-single-big-problem-or-big-theory&#34;&gt;Don’t prematurely obsess on a single &amp;ldquo;big problem&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;big theory&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Millions long for immortality who do not know what to do with themselves on a rainy Sunday afternoon.&#xA;— Susan Ertz, &amp;ldquo;Anger in the Sky&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a particularly dangerous occupational hazard in this subject: one can become focused, to the exclusion of other mathematical activity (and in extreme cases, on non-mathematical activity also), on a single really difficult problem in a field (or on some grand unifying theory) before one is really ready (both in terms of mathematical preparation, and also in terms of one&amp;rsquo;s career) to devote so much of one&amp;rsquo;s research time to such a project. This is doubly true if one has not yet &lt;strong&gt;learnt the limitations of one&amp;rsquo;s tools&lt;/strong&gt; or acquired a healthy &lt;strong&gt;scepticism of one&amp;rsquo;s own work&lt;/strong&gt;, as this can lead to the humiliating spectacle of proudly announcing a major breakthrough on a well known problem, only to withdraw the preprint shortly afterwards after serious flaws (often arising from pushing a method well beyond its known limits, and encounting obstructions beyond those limits that were known to the experts) are pointed out in the manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be flexible</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/be-flexible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/be-flexible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/be-flexible.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/be-flexible/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;be-flexible&#34;&gt;Be flexible&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is not the strongest of the species that survives, nor the most intelligent, but the one most responsive to change.&#xA;(Leon C. Megginson)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mathematical research is by its nature unpredictable – if we knew in advance what the answer would be and how to do it, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be research! You should therefore be prepared for research to lead you in unexpected directions, and it may end up that you may find a new problem or area of mathematics more interesting than the one you were initially working in. (See also &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to learn things outside your field&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Learn the power of other mathematician&amp;rsquo;s tools&amp;rdquo;.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attend talks and conferences, even those not directly related to your work</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/attend-talks-and-conferences-even-those-not-directly-related-to-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/attend-talks-and-conferences-even-those-not-directly-related-to-your-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/attend-talks-and-conferences-even-those-not-directly-related-to-your-work.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/attend-talks-and-conferences-even-those-not-directly-related-to-your-work/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;attend-talks-and-conferences-even-those-not-directly-related-to-your-work&#34;&gt;Attend talks and conferences, even those not directly related to your work&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Know how to listen, and you will profit even from those who talk badly.&#xA;— Plutarch&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern mathematics is very much a collaborative activity rather than an individual one. You need to know what&amp;rsquo;s going on elsewhere in mathematics, and what other mathematicians find interesting; this will often give valuable perspectives on your own work. This is true not just for talks in your immediate field, but also in nearby fields. (For much the same reason, I recommend studying at different places.) An inspiring talk can also increase your motivation in your own work and in the field of mathematics in general.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take the initiative</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/take-the-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/take-the-initiative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/take-the-initiative.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/take-the-initiative/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;take-the-initiative&#34;&gt;Take the initiative&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best teacher is the one who suggests rather than dogmatizes, and inspires his listener with the wish to teach himself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— Edward Bulwer-Lytton&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While you should &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;talk to your advisor&lt;/a&gt;, you should not be completely reliant on him or her; after all, you are going to have to do mathematics primarily on your own once you graduate!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you feel like you want to learn something, do something, or write something, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to clear it with your advisor – just go ahead and do it (though in some cases other priorities, such as writing your thesis, may be temporarily more important, and you should of course keep your advisor updated as to what you&amp;rsquo;re doing mathematically). Research your library or the internet, talk with other graduate students or faculty, read papers and books on your own (both &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;in your field&lt;/a&gt; and in &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;nearby fields&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;attend conferences&lt;/a&gt;, and so forth. (See also &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;ask yourself dumb questions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study at different places</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/study-at-different-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/study-at-different-places/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/study-at-different-places.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/study-at-different-places/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;study-at-different-places&#34;&gt;Study at different places&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The three pillars of learning; seeing much, suffering much, and studying much.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(Welsh triad; later attributed to Benjamin Disraeli)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a very good idea to do your graduate study at a different institution as your undergraduate study, and to take a postdoctoral position at a different place from where you did your graduate study.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even the best mathematics departments do not have strengths in every field, so being at several mathematics departments will broaden your education and expose you to a variety of mathematical cultures, including &lt;strong&gt;interesting tools&lt;/strong&gt; and parts of mathematics &lt;strong&gt;outside of your existing fields of expertise&lt;/strong&gt;. Furthermore, you will be able to interact over time with a greater number of mathematicians in your area if you study and work at different places, than if you stay at a single institution; given that a significant portion of one&amp;rsquo;s career advancement in a field is based in part on the recognition you and your work receive from your peers in that field, this can thus be quite beneficial to your future career in a mathematical area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Think ahead</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/think-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/think-ahead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/think-ahead.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/think-ahead/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;think-ahead&#34;&gt;Think ahead&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Worse than being blind, is to see and have no vision.&#xA;— Helen Keller&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is really easy to get bogged down in the details of some work and not recall the purpose of what one is actually doing; thus it is good to pause every now and then and recall &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; one is pursuing a particular goal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For instance, if one is trying to prove a &lt;strong&gt;lemma&lt;/strong&gt; for one reason or another, take a few moments to ask yourself questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be sceptical of your own work</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/be-sceptical-of-your-own-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/be-sceptical-of-your-own-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/be-sceptical-of-your-own-work.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/be-sceptical-of-your-own-work/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;be-sceptical-of-your-own-work&#34;&gt;Be sceptical of your own work&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An expert is a man who has made all the mistakes, which can be made, in a very narrow field.&#xA;— Niels Bohr&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you unexpectedly find a problem solving itself almost effortlessly, and you can&amp;rsquo;t quite see why, you should try to analyse your solution more sceptically.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In particular, the method may also be able to prove much stronger statements which are known to be false, which would imply that there is a flaw in the method.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask yourself dumb questions – and answer them!</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/ask-yourself-dumb-questions-and-answer-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/ask-yourself-dumb-questions-and-answer-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/ask-yourself-dumb-questions-and-answer-them.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/ask-yourself-dumb-questions-and-answer-them/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;ask-yourself-dumb-questions--and-answer-them&#34;&gt;Ask yourself dumb questions – and answer them!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don’t just read it; fight it! Ask your own questions, look for your own examples, discover your own proofs. Is the hypothesis necessary? Is the converse true? What happens in the classical special case? What about the degenerate cases? Where does the proof use the hypothesis?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Paul Halmos, &amp;ldquo;I want to be a mathematician&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you learn mathematics, whether in books or in lectures, you generally only see the end product – very polished, clever and elegant presentations of a mathematical topic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn the power of other mathematicians’ tools</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/learn-the-power-of-other-mathematicians-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/learn-the-power-of-other-mathematicians-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/learn-the-power-of-other-mathematicians-tools.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/learn-the-power-of-other-mathematicians-tools/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;learn-the-power-of-other-mathematicians-tools&#34;&gt;Learn the power of other mathematicians&amp;rsquo; tools&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I suppose it is tempting, if the only tool you have is a hammer, to treat everything as if it were a nail.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— Abraham Maslow, &amp;ldquo;Psychology of Science&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will find, when listening to talks or reading papers, that there will be problems which interest you which were solved using an unfamiliar tool, but seem &lt;strong&gt;out of reach of your own personal &amp;ldquo;bag of tricks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. When this happens, you should try to see whether your own tools can in fact accomplish a similar task, but you should also try to work out what made the other tool so effective – for instance, to locate the simplest model case in which that tool does something non-trivial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn the limitations of your tools</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/learn-the-limitations-of-your-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/learn-the-limitations-of-your-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/learn-the-limitations-of-your-tools.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/learn-the-limitations-of-your-tools/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;learn-the-limitations-of-your-tools&#34;&gt;Learn the limitations of your tools&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An education isn’t how much you have committed to memory, or even how much you know. It’s being able to differentiate between what you do know and what you don’t.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anatole France&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mathematical education (and research papers) tends to focus, naturally enough, on techniques that work. But it is equally important to know when the tools you have &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; work, so that you don&amp;rsquo;t waste time on a strategy which is doomed from the start, and instead go hunting for new tools to solve the problem (or hunt for a new problem).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t be afraid to learn things outside your field</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/dont-be-afraid-to-learn-things-outside-your-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/dont-be-afraid-to-learn-things-outside-your-field/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/dont-be-afraid-to-learn-things-outside-your-field.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/dont-be-afraid-to-learn-things-outside-your-field/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;dont-be-afraid-to-learn-things-outside-your-field&#34;&gt;Don’t be afraid to learn things outside your field&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Try to learn something about everything and everything about something.&#xA;— Thomas Huxley&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maths phobia is a pervasive problem in the wider community. Unfortunately, it sometimes also exists among professional mathematicians (together with its distant cousin, maths snobbery).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If it turns out that in order to make progress on your problem, you have to learn some external piece of mathematics, this is a &lt;strong&gt;good thing&lt;/strong&gt; – your own &lt;strong&gt;mathematical range will increase&lt;/strong&gt;, you will have acquired &lt;strong&gt;some new tools&lt;/strong&gt;, and your work will become more interesting, both to people in your field and also to people in the external field.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn and relearn your field</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/learn-and-relearn-your-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/learn-and-relearn-your-field/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/learn-and-relearn-your-field.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/learn-and-relearn-your-field/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;learn-and-relearn-your-field&#34;&gt;Learn and relearn your field&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even fairly good students, when they have obtained the solution of the problem and written down neatly the argument, shut their books and look for something else. Doing so, they miss an important and instructive phase of the work. … A good teacher should understand and impress on his students the view that no problem whatever is completely exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the first and foremost duties of the teacher is not to give his students the impression that mathematical problems have little connection with each other, and no connection at all with anything else. We have a natural opportunity to investigate the connections of a problem when looking back at its solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t base career decisions on glamour or fame</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/dont-base-career-decisions-on-glamour-or-fame/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:52:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/dont-base-career-decisions-on-glamour-or-fame/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/dont-base-career-decisions-on-glamour-or-fame.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/dont-base-career-decisions-on-glamour-or-fame/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;dont-base-career-decisions-on-glamour-or-fame&#34;&gt;Don’t base career decisions on glamour or fame&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;行名失己, 非士也 [One who pursues fame at the risk of losing one&amp;rsquo;s self, is not a scholar].&#xA;(&#xA;莊子 [Zhuangzi]&#xA;, &amp;quot;&#xA;大宗師 [The Grandmaster]&amp;quot;&#xA;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Going into a field or department simply because it is glamorous is not a good idea, nor is focusing on the most famous problems (or mathematicians) within a field, solely because they are famous – honestly, there isn&amp;rsquo;t that much fame or glamour in mathematics overall, and it is not worth chasing these things as your primary goal. Anything glamorous is likely to be highly competitive, and only those with the most solid of backgrounds (in particular, lots of experience with less glamorous aspects of the field) are likely to get anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enjoy your work</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/enjoy-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/enjoy-your-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/enjoy-your-work.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/enjoy-your-work/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;enjoy-your-work&#34;&gt;Enjoy your work&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No profit grows where is no pleasure ta&amp;rsquo;en;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In brief, sir, study what you most affect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— William Shakespeare, &lt;em&gt;The Taming of the Shrew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To really get anywhere in mathematics requires &lt;strong&gt;hard work&lt;/strong&gt;. If you don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy what you are doing, and do not derive satisfaction from your contributions, it will be difficult to put in the sustained amounts of energy required to succeed in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work hard</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/work-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/work-hard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/work-hard.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/work-hard/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;work-hard&#34;&gt;Work hard&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every mathematician worthy of the name has experienced … the state of lucid exaltation in which one thought succeeds another as if miraculously… this feeling may last for hours at a time, even for days. Once you have experienced it, you are eager to repeat it but unable to do it at will, unless perhaps by dogged work…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;André Weil, &amp;ldquo;The Apprenticeship of a Mathematician&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relying on intelligence alone to pull things off at the last minute may work for a while, but, generally speaking, at the graduate level or higher it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s more to mathematics than rigour and proofs</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-rigour-and-proofs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-rigour-and-proofs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-rigour-and-proofs.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-rigour-and-proofs/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;theres-more-to-mathematics-than-rigour-and-proofs&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more to mathematics than rigour and proofs&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The history of every major galactic civilization tends to pass through three distinct and recognizable phases, those of Survival, Inquiry and Sophistication, otherwise known as the How, Why, and Where phases. For instance, the first phase is characterized by the question &amp;lsquo;How can we eat?&amp;rsquo;, the second by the question &amp;lsquo;Why do we eat?&amp;rsquo; and the third by the question, &amp;lsquo;Where shall we have lunch?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s more to mathematics than grades and exams and methods</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods&#34;&gt;There’s more to mathematics than grades and exams and methods&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you have mastered numbers, you will in fact no longer be reading numbers, any more than you read words when reading books. You will be reading meanings.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(Harold Geneen, &amp;ldquo;Managing&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When learning mathematics as an undergraduate student, there is often a heavy emphasis on grade averages, and on exams which often emphasize memorisation of techniques and theory than on actual conceptual understanding, or on either intellectual or intuitive thought. There are good reasons for this; there is a certain amount of theory and technique that must be practiced before one can really get anywhere in mathematics (much as there is a certain amount of drill required before one can play a musical instrument well). It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how much innate mathematical talent and intuition you have; if you are unable to, say, compute a multidimensional integral, manipulate matrix equations, understand abstract definitions, or correctly set up a proof by induction, then it is unlikely that you will be able to work effectively with higher mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advice on mathematics competitions</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/advice-on-mathematics-competitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/advice-on-mathematics-competitions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/advice-on-mathematics-competitions.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/advice-on-mathematics-competitions/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;advice-on-mathematics-competitions&#34;&gt;Advice on mathematics competitions&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sports serve society by providing vivid examples of excellence.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;— George Will&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I greatly enjoyed my experiences with high school mathematics competitions (all the way back in the 1980s!). Like any other school sporting event, there is a certain level of excitement in participating with peers with similar interests and talents in a competitive activity. At the Olympiad levels, there is also the opportunity to travel nationally and internationally, which is an experience I strongly recommend for all high-school students.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMS Notices Of The American Mathematical Society</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/ams-notices-of-the-american-mathematical-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/ams-notices-of-the-american-mathematical-society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/ams-notices-of-the-american-mathematical-society.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ams.org/cgi-bin/notices/nxgnotices.pl?fm=gen&amp;amp;cnt=career&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;ams--notices-of-the-american-mathematical-society&#34;&gt;AMS :: Notices Of The American Mathematical Society&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notices of the American Mathematical Society&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the current issue of the Notices of the American Mathematical Society. With support from AMS membership, we are pleased to share the journal with the global mathematical community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;previous-issue&#34;&gt;Previous Issue&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume 72 | Number 10 | November 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No newer issues&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;career&#34;&gt;Career&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Information and suggestions for graduate students, job seekers, early career mathematicians of all types, and mentors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For potential Ph.D. students</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/for-potential-phd-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/for-potential-phd-students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/for-potential-phd-students.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://math.stanford.edu/~vakil/potentialstudents.html&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-potential-phd-students&#34;&gt;For potential Ph.D. students&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the next few years, I may take on a few additional Ph.D. students, although times may come when I&amp;rsquo;ll be too full (e.g. a time that ended recently). This page is intended for those considering working with me, although it also contains some tips for graduate students in general, as well as an idea of what I expect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Algebraic geometry (or at least my take on it) is a technical subject that also requires a good deal of background in other subjects, as well as geometric intuition. So before I take you on as a new student, you should be comfortable with the foundations of the subject, which means having done the majority of the exercises in Hartshorne or my course notes, and being able to explain them on demand. (You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do this on your own; I&amp;rsquo;m happy talking with you through this process.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Princeton Companion to Mathematics</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/the-princeton-companion-to-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/the-princeton-companion-to-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/the-princeton-companion-to-mathematics.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://press.princeton.edu/titles/8350.html&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-princeton-companion-to-mathematics&#34;&gt;The Princeton Companion to Mathematics&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edited by Timothy Gowers, June Barrow-Green, and Imre Leader&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ultimate mathematics reference book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication-details&#34;&gt;Publication Details&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hardcover&#34;&gt;Hardcover&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $110.00/£92.00&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ISBN:&lt;/strong&gt; 9780691118802&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published:&lt;/strong&gt; Sep 28, 2008&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copyright:&lt;/strong&gt; 2009&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pages:&lt;/strong&gt; 1056&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 8 x 10 in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Illus:&lt;/strong&gt; Black-and-white illustrations throughout | Cross-references, bibliographies, index&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ebook-epub-via-app&#34;&gt;ebook (EPUB via app)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $110.00/£92.00&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ISBN:&lt;/strong&gt; 9780691118802&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published:&lt;/strong&gt; Sep 28, 2008&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copyright:&lt;/strong&gt; 2009&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pages:&lt;/strong&gt; 1056&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 8 x 10 in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Illus:&lt;/strong&gt; Black-and-white illustrations throughout | Cross-references, bibliographies, index&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ebook-pdf-via-app&#34;&gt;ebook (PDF via app)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $110.00/£92.00&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ISBN:&lt;/strong&gt; 9780691118802&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published:&lt;/strong&gt; Sep 28, 2008&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copyright:&lt;/strong&gt; 2009&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pages:&lt;/strong&gt; 1056&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 8 x 10 in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Illus:&lt;/strong&gt; Black-and-white illustrations throughout | Cross-references, bibliographies, index&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a one-of-a-kind reference for anyone with a serious interest in mathematics. Edited by Timothy Gowers, a recipient of the Fields Medal, it presents nearly two hundred entries—written especially for this book by some of the world&amp;rsquo;s leading mathematicians—that introduce basic mathematical tools and vocabulary; trace the development of modern mathematics; explain essential terms and concepts; examine core ideas in major areas of mathematics; describe the achievements of scores of famous mathematicians; explore the impact of mathematics on other disciplines such as biology, finance, and music—and much, much more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
