<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:05:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Write down what you’ve done</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/write-down-what-youve-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/write-down-what-youve-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/zh/write-down-what-youve-done.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/write-down-what-youve-done/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;write-down-what-youve-done&#34;&gt;Write down what you’ve done&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every composer knows the anguish and despair occasioned by forgetting ideas which one had no time to write down.&#xA;— Hector Berlioz&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were many occasions early in my career when I read, heard about, or stumbled upon some neat mathematical trick or argument, and thought I understood it well enough that I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to write it down; and then, say six months later, when I actually needed to recall that trick, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t reconstruct it at all. Eventually I resolved to write down (preferably on a computer) a sketch of any interesting argument I came across – not necessarily at a publication level of quality, but detailed enough that I could then safely forget about the details, and readily recover the argument from the sketch whenever the need arises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use the wastebasket</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/use-the-wastebasket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/use-the-wastebasket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/zh/use-the-wastebasket.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/use-the-wastebasket/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;use-the-wastebasket&#34;&gt;Use the wastebasket&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a mistake to suppose that men succeed through success; they much oftener succeed through failures. Precept, study, advice, and example could never have taught them so well as failure has done.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Samuel Smiles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not every idea leads to a success, and not every first draft forms a good template for the final draft.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is true even for the very best mathematicians.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are times when a project just isn&amp;rsquo;t working the way it was initially planned, and you have to scale it down, refocus it, or shelve it altogether; or a lemma that you spent a lot of time on turns out not to add anything much to the paper and has to be reluctantly jettisoned or deferred to another paper; or that the structure of a half-written paper is clearly not optimal and that one needs to rewrite the entire thing from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attend talks and conferences, even those not directly related to your work</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/attend-talks-and-conferences-even-those-not-directly-related-to-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/attend-talks-and-conferences-even-those-not-directly-related-to-your-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/zh/attend-talks-and-conferences-even-those-not-directly-related-to-your-work.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/attend-talks-and-conferences-even-those-not-directly-related-to-your-work/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;attend-talks-and-conferences-even-those-not-directly-related-to-your-work&#34;&gt;Attend talks and conferences, even those not directly related to your work&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Know how to listen, and you will profit even from those who talk badly.&#xA;— Plutarch&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern mathematics is very much a collaborative activity rather than an individual one. You need to know what&amp;rsquo;s going on elsewhere in mathematics, and what other mathematicians find interesting; this will often give valuable perspectives on your own work. This is true not just for talks in your immediate field, but also in nearby fields. (For much the same reason, I recommend studying at different places.) An inspiring talk can also increase your motivation in your own work and in the field of mathematics in general.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s more to mathematics than grades and exams and methods</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/zh/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods&#34;&gt;There’s more to mathematics than grades and exams and methods&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you have mastered numbers, you will in fact no longer be reading numbers, any more than you read words when reading books. You will be reading meanings.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(Harold Geneen, &amp;ldquo;Managing&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When learning mathematics as an undergraduate student, there is often a heavy emphasis on grade averages, and on exams which often emphasize memorisation of techniques and theory than on actual conceptual understanding, or on either intellectual or intuitive thought. There are good reasons for this; there is a certain amount of theory and technique that must be practiced before one can really get anywhere in mathematics (much as there is a certain amount of drill required before one can play a musical instrument well). It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how much innate mathematical talent and intuition you have; if you are unable to, say, compute a multidimensional integral, manipulate matrix equations, understand abstract definitions, or correctly set up a proof by induction, then it is unlikely that you will be able to work effectively with higher mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Being a Noob</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/noob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/noob/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/noob/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;being-a-noob&#34;&gt;Being a Noob&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was young, I thought old people had everything figured out. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m old, I know this isn&amp;rsquo;t true.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I constantly feel like a noob. It seems like I&amp;rsquo;m always talking to some startup working in a new field I know nothing about, or reading a book about a topic I don&amp;rsquo;t understand well enough, or visiting some new country where I don&amp;rsquo;t know how things work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copy What You Like</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/copy/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;copy-what-you-like&#34;&gt;Copy What You Like&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school I spent a lot of time imitating bad writers. What we studied in English classes was mostly fiction, so I assumed that was the highest form of writing. Mistake number one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The stories that seemed to be most admired were ones in which people suffered in complicated ways. Anything funny or gripping was ipso facto suspect, unless it was old enough to be hard to understand, like Shakespeare or Chaucer. Mistake number two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Get New Ideas</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/getideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/getideas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/getideas/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-get-new-ideas&#34;&gt;How to Get New Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Someone fed my essays into GPT to make something that could answer questions based on them, then asked it where good ideas come from. The answer was ok, but not what I would have said. This is what I would have said.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The way to get new ideas is to notice anomalies: what seems strange, or missing, or broken? You can see anomalies in everyday life (much of standup comedy is based on this), but the best place to look for them is at the frontiers of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How You Know</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/know/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-you-know&#34;&gt;How You Know&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read Villehardouin&amp;rsquo;s chronicle of the Fourth Crusade at least two times, maybe three. And yet if I had to write down everything I remember from it, I doubt it would amount to much more than a page. Multiply this times several hundred, and I get an uneasy feeling when I look at my bookshelves. What use is it to read all these books if I remember so little from them?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laundry</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/laundry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/laundry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/laundry/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;laundry&#34;&gt;Laundry&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Version 1.0&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As E. B. White said, &amp;ldquo;good writing is rewriting.&amp;rdquo; I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize this when I was in school. In writing, as in math and science, they only show you the finished product. You don&amp;rsquo;t see all the false starts. This gives students a misleading view of how things get made.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason it happens is that writers don&amp;rsquo;t want people to see their mistakes. But I&amp;rsquo;m willing to let people see an early draft if it will show how much you have to rewrite to beat an essay into shape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superlinear Returns</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/superlinear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/superlinear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/superlinear/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;superlinear-returns&#34;&gt;Superlinear Returns&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand about the world when I was a child is the degree to which the returns for performance are superlinear.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Teachers and coaches implicitly told us the returns were linear. &amp;ldquo;You get out,&amp;rdquo; I heard a thousand times, &amp;ldquo;what you put in.&amp;rdquo; They meant well, but this is rarely true. If your product is only half as good as your competitor&amp;rsquo;s, you don&amp;rsquo;t get half as many customers. You get no customers, and you go out of business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bus Ticket Theory of Genius</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/genius/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/genius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/genius/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-bus-ticket-theory-of-genius&#34;&gt;The Bus Ticket Theory of Genius&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2019&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows that to do great work you need both natural ability and determination. But there&amp;rsquo;s a third ingredient that&amp;rsquo;s not as well understood: an obsessive interest in a particular topic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To explain this point I need to burn my reputation with some group of people, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to choose bus ticket collectors. There are people who collect old bus tickets. Like many collectors, they have an obsessive interest in the minutiae of what they collect. They can keep track of distinctions between different types of bus tickets that would be hard for the rest of us to remember. Because we don&amp;rsquo;t care enough. What&amp;rsquo;s the point of spending so much time thinking about old bus tickets?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lesson to Unlearn</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/lesson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/lesson/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-lesson-to-unlearn&#34;&gt;The Lesson to Unlearn&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2019&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most damaging thing you learned in school wasn&amp;rsquo;t something you learned in any specific class. It was learning to get good grades.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was in college, a particularly earnest philosophy grad student once told me that he never cared what grade he got in a class, only what he learned in it. This stuck in my mind because it was the only time I ever heard anyone say such a thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Need to Read</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/read/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/read/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-need-to-read&#34;&gt;The Need to Read&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the science fiction books I read as a kid, reading had often been replaced by some more efficient way of acquiring knowledge. Mysterious &amp;ldquo;tapes&amp;rdquo; would load it into one&amp;rsquo;s brain like a program being loaded into a computer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That sort of thing is unlikely to happen anytime soon. Not just because it would be hard to build a replacement for reading, but because even if one existed, it would be insufficient. Reading about x doesn&amp;rsquo;t just teach you about x; it also teaches you how to write. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Lisp</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/acl2txtt1748944359/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/acl2txtt1748944359/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/acl2txtt1748944359/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-lisp&#34;&gt;Welcome to Lisp&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter aims to get you programming as soon as possible. By the end of it you will know enough Common Lisp to begin writing programs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;21-form&#34;&gt;2.1 Form&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is particularly true of Lisp that you learn it by using it, because Lisp is an interactive language. Any Lisp system will include an interactive front-end called the toplevel. You type Lisp expressions into the toplevel, and the system displays their values. Lisp usually displays a prompt to tell you that it&amp;rsquo;s waiting for you to type something. Many implementations of Common Lisp use &amp;gt; as the toplevel prompt. That&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;ll use here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve Learned from Users</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/users/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-ive-learned-from-users&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve Learned from Users&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently told applicants to Y Combinator that the best advice I could give for getting in, per word, was &amp;ldquo;Explain what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned from users.&amp;rdquo; That tests a lot of things: whether you&amp;rsquo;re paying attention to users, how well you understand them, and even how much they need what you&amp;rsquo;re making.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Afterward I asked myself the same question. What have I learned from YC&amp;rsquo;s users, the startups we&amp;rsquo;ve funded?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Smart People Have Bad Ideas</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/bronze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/bronze/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/bronze/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-smart-people-have-bad-ideas&#34;&gt;Why Smart People Have Bad Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This summer, as an experiment, some friends and I are giving seed funding to a bunch of new startups. It&amp;rsquo;s an experiment because we&amp;rsquo;re prepared to fund younger founders than most investors would. That&amp;rsquo;s why we&amp;rsquo;re doing it during the summer—so even college students can participate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We know from Google and Yahoo that grad students can start successful startups. And we know from experience that some undergrads are as capable as most grad students. The accepted age for startup founders has been creeping downward. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to find the lower bound.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
