<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker Culture on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1326/tags/hacker-culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hacker Culture on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1326/tags/hacker-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Being Popular</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/popular/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/popular/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/popular/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;being-popular&#34;&gt;Being Popular&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2001&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This article was written as a kind of business plan for a new language. So it is missing (because it takes for granted) the most important feature of a good programming language: very powerful abstractions.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine once told an eminent operating systems expert that he wanted to design a really good programming language. The expert told him that it would be a waste of time, that programming languages don&amp;rsquo;t become popular or unpopular based on their merits, and so no matter how good his language was, no one would use it. At least, that was what had happened to the language he had designed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Happened to Yahoo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/yahoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/yahoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/yahoo/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-happened-to-yahoo&#34;&gt;What Happened to Yahoo&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2010When I went to work for Yahoo after they bought our startup in 1998, it felt like the center of the world. It was supposed to be the next big thing. It was supposed to be what Google turned out to be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What went wrong? The problems that hosed Yahoo go back a long time, practically to the beginning of the company. They were already very visible when I got there in 1998. Yahoo had two problems Google didn&amp;rsquo;t: easy money, and ambivalence about being a technology company.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
