<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/categories/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 20:01:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On writing</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 20:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/on-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/on-writing.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/advice-on-writing-papers/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-writing&#34;&gt;On writing&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are three rules for writing the novel. Unfortunately, no one knows what they are.&#xA;— W. Somerset Maugham&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everyone has to &lt;strong&gt;develop their own writing style&lt;/strong&gt;, based on their own strengths and weaknesses, on the subject matter, on the target audience, and sometimes on the target medium. As such, it is virtually impossible to prescribe rigid rules for writing that encompass all conceivable situations and styles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write down what you’ve done</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/write-down-what-youve-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/write-down-what-youve-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/write-down-what-youve-done.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/write-down-what-youve-done/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;write-down-what-youve-done&#34;&gt;Write down what you’ve done&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every composer knows the anguish and despair occasioned by forgetting ideas which one had no time to write down.&#xA;— Hector Berlioz&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were many occasions early in my career when I read, heard about, or stumbled upon some neat mathematical trick or argument, and thought I understood it well enough that I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to write it down; and then, say six months later, when I actually needed to recall that trick, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t reconstruct it at all. Eventually I resolved to write down (preferably on a computer) a sketch of any interesting argument I came across – not necessarily at a publication level of quality, but detailed enough that I could then safely forget about the details, and readily recover the argument from the sketch whenever the need arises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use the wastebasket</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/use-the-wastebasket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/use-the-wastebasket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/use-the-wastebasket.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/use-the-wastebasket/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;use-the-wastebasket&#34;&gt;Use the wastebasket&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a mistake to suppose that men succeed through success; they much oftener succeed through failures. Precept, study, advice, and example could never have taught them so well as failure has done.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Samuel Smiles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not every idea leads to a success, and not every first draft forms a good template for the final draft.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is true even for the very best mathematicians.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are times when a project just isn&amp;rsquo;t working the way it was initially planned, and you have to scale it down, refocus it, or shelve it altogether; or a lemma that you spent a lot of time on turns out not to add anything much to the paper and has to be reluctantly jettisoned or deferred to another paper; or that the structure of a half-written paper is clearly not optimal and that one needs to rewrite the entire thing from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
