<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exposition on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/exposition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exposition on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:26:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/exposition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Be considerate of your audience</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/be-considerate-of-your-audience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/be-considerate-of-your-audience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/be-considerate-of-your-audience.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/be-considerate-of-your-audience/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;be-considerate-of-your-audience&#34;&gt;Be considerate of your audience&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think like a wise man, but communicate in the language of the people.&#xA;— William Butler Yeats&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This advice applies primarily to papers, but also to lectures and seminars (though one should also bear in mind that talks are not the same as papers).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, one of the most important things in mathematics (though certainly not the only thing) is to get results, and prove them correctly. However, one also needs to make a good faith effort to communicate these results to their intended audience. (It may feel like you have attained some level of intellectual achievement if you can discuss a topic which is so difficult or jargon-heavy that most of your audience do not understand what you are talking about, but it is in fact a far greater intellectual achievement if you can actually communicate that difficult topic effectively to such an audience.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn and relearn your field</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/learn-and-relearn-your-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/learn-and-relearn-your-field/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/learn-and-relearn-your-field.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/learn-and-relearn-your-field/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;learn-and-relearn-your-field&#34;&gt;Learn and relearn your field&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even fairly good students, when they have obtained the solution of the problem and written down neatly the argument, shut their books and look for something else. Doing so, they miss an important and instructive phase of the work. … A good teacher should understand and impress on his students the view that no problem whatever is completely exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the first and foremost duties of the teacher is not to give his students the impression that mathematical problems have little connection with each other, and no connection at all with anything else. We have a natural opportunity to investigate the connections of a problem when looking back at its solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
