<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Critical Thinking on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/critical-thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Critical Thinking on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/critical-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Disagree</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/disagree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/disagree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/disagree/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-disagree&#34;&gt;How to Disagree&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The web is turning writing into a conversation. Twenty years ago, writers wrote and readers read. The web lets readers respond, and increasingly they do—in comment threads, on forums, and in their own blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many who respond to something disagree with it. That&amp;rsquo;s to be expected. Agreeing tends to motivate people less than disagreeing. And when you agree there&amp;rsquo;s less to say. You could expand on something the author said, but he has probably already explored the most interesting implications. When you disagree you&amp;rsquo;re entering territory he may not have explored.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keep Your Identity Small</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/identity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/identity/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;keep-your-identity-small&#34;&gt;Keep Your Identity Small&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;February 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I finally realized today why politics and religion yield such uniquely useless discussions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a rule, any mention of religion on an online forum degenerates into a religious argument. Why? Why does this happen with religion and not with Javascript or baking or other topics people talk about on forums?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s different about religion is that people don&amp;rsquo;t feel they need to have any particular expertise to have opinions about it. All they need is strongly held beliefs, and anyone can have those. No thread about Javascript will grow as fast as one about religion, because people feel they have to be over some threshold of expertise to post comments about that. But on religion everyone&amp;rsquo;s an expert.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
