<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paper Writing on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/paper-writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paper Writing on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 09:03:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/paper-writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Write a rapid prototype first</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/en/write-a-rapid-prototype-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 09:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/en/write-a-rapid-prototype-first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/zh/write-a-rapid-prototype-first.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/advice-on-writing-papers/write-a-rapid-prototype-first/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;write-a-rapid-prototype-first&#34;&gt;Write a rapid prototype first&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best performance improvement is the transition from the nonworking state to the working state.&#xA;— John Ousterhout&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discovering a solution to a mathematical problem is only half of the battle. Actually writing down the argument that you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered formally can also be a daunting task, especially if the argument is lengthy and is not modeled on an existing one in the literature. While every individual detail of the argument may be clear to the author, the overall structure of the argument may not be immediately obvious. In particular, it is often difficult to make the (important) decisions about the:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use good notation</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/en/use-good-notation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/en/use-good-notation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/zh/use-good-notation.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/advice-on-writing-papers/use-good-notation/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;use-good-notation&#34;&gt;Use good notation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By relieving the brain of all unnecessary work, a good notation sets it free to concentrate on more advanced problems, and, in effect, increases the mental power of the race.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— Alfred North Whitehead, &amp;ldquo;An Introduction to Mathematics&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good notation can make the difference between a readable paper and an unreadable one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ideally, notation should emphasize the most important parameters and features of a mathematical expression or statement, while downplaying the routine or uninteresting parameters and features. For instance, if one does not care much about the exact values of constants in estimates, then notation which conceals these constants (such as $O()$, $\ll$, or $\lesssim$) are useful; conversely, these notations should be avoided if the precise values of these constants are of importance to the paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On writing</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 20:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/on-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/zh/on-writing.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/advice-on-writing-papers/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article is an important one and serves as the main page for the academic writing topic on Terry Tao&amp;rsquo;s blog. There are many links in this article, and the corresponding articles have not been translated on this site yet. Therefore, clicking the links in this article will directly jump to the original article on Terry Tao&amp;rsquo;s blog. Please feel free to check them out!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are three rules for writing the novel. Unfortunately, no one knows what they are.&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/W._Somerset_Maugham&#34;&gt;W. Somerset Maugham&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be considerate of your audience</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/be-considerate-of-your-audience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/be-considerate-of-your-audience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/zh/be-considerate-of-your-audience.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/be-considerate-of-your-audience/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;be-considerate-of-your-audience&#34;&gt;Be considerate of your audience&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think like a wise man, but communicate in the language of the people.&#xA;— William Butler Yeats&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This advice applies primarily to papers, but also to lectures and seminars (though one should also bear in mind that talks are not the same as papers).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, one of the most important things in mathematics (though certainly not the only thing) is to get results, and prove them correctly. However, one also needs to make a good faith effort to communicate these results to their intended audience. (It may feel like you have attained some level of intellectual achievement if you can discuss a topic which is so difficult or jargon-heavy that most of your audience do not understand what you are talking about, but it is in fact a far greater intellectual achievement if you can actually communicate that difficult topic effectively to such an audience.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to write a paper</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/en/how-to-write-a-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/en/how-to-write-a-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/zh/how-to-write-a-paper.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wisdom.weizmann.ac.il/%7Eoded/writing.html&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-write-a-paper&#34;&gt;How to write a paper&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this essay is to make some self-evident (yet often ignored) remarks about how to write a paper. We argue that the key to writing well is full awareness of the role of papers in the scientific process and full implementation of the principles, derived from this awareness, in the writing process. We also provide some concrete suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The current essay is a revised and augmented version of our essay &amp;ldquo;How NOT to write a paper&amp;rdquo; (written in 1991, revised 1996). Originally, we confined ourselves to general principles and concrete negative comments. Here we overcame our reservation towards positive suggestions; hence the change in the essay&amp;rsquo;s title.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
