<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1326/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1326/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve Learned from Hacker News</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/hackernews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/hackernews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/hackernews/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-ive-learned-from-hacker-news&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve Learned from Hacker News&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;February 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hacker News was two years old last week. Initially it was supposed to be a side project—an application to sharpen Arc on, and a place for current and future Y Combinator founders to exchange news. It&amp;rsquo;s grown bigger and taken up more time than I expected, but I don&amp;rsquo;t regret that because I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so much from working on it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;growth&#34;&gt;Growth&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we launched in February 2007, weekday traffic was around 1600 daily uniques. It&amp;rsquo;s since grown to around 22,000. This growth rate is a bit higher than I&amp;rsquo;d like. I&amp;rsquo;d like the site to grow, since a site that isn&amp;rsquo;t growing at least slowly is probably dead. But I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want it to grow as large as Digg or Reddit—mainly because that would dilute the character of the site, but also because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend all my time dealing with scaling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Startup Hubs Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/hubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/hubs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/hubs/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-startup-hubs-work&#34;&gt;Why Startup Hubs Work&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2011&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you look at a list of US cities sorted by population, the number of successful startups per capita varies by orders of magnitude. Somehow it&amp;rsquo;s as if most places were sprayed with startupicide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wondered about this for years. I could see the average town was like a roach motel for startup ambitions: smart, ambitious people went in, but no startups came out. But I was never able to figure out exactly what happened inside the motel—exactly what was killing all the potential startups. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
