<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Linguista</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1355/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1355/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>6,631,372</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/6631327/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/6631327/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/6631327/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;6631372&#34;&gt;6,631,372&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6,631,372 March 2006, rev August 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago I found to my surprise that I&amp;rsquo;d been granted a patent. It issued in 2003, but no one told me. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know about it now except that a few months ago, while visiting Yahoo, I happened to run into a Big Cheese I knew from working there in the late nineties. He brought up something called Revenue Loop, which Viaweb had been working on when they bought us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Local Revolution?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/revolution/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-local-revolution&#34;&gt;A Local Revolution?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently I realized I&amp;rsquo;d been holding two ideas in my head that would explode if combined.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first is that startups may represent a new economic phase, on the scale of the Industrial Revolution. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure of this, but there seems a decent chance it&amp;rsquo;s true. People are dramatically more productive as founders or early employees of startups—imagine how much less Larry and Sergey would have achieved if they&amp;rsquo;d gone to work for a big company—and that scale of improvement can change social customs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addiction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/addiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/addiction/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;addiction&#34;&gt;Addiction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Acceleration of Addictiveness July 2010&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What hard liquor, cigarettes, heroin, and crack have in common is that they&amp;rsquo;re all more concentrated forms of less addictive predecessors. Most if not all the things we describe as addictive are. And the scary thing is, the process that created them is accelerating.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to stop it. It&amp;rsquo;s the same process that cures diseases: technological progress. Technological progress means making things do more of what we want. When the thing we want is something we want to want, we consider technological progress good. If some new technique makes solar cells x% more efficient, that seems strictly better. When progress concentrates something we don&amp;rsquo;t want to want — when it transforms opium into heroin — it seems bad. But it&amp;rsquo;s the same process at work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beating the Averages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/avg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/avg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/avg/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;beating-the-averages&#34;&gt;Beating the Averages&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator. April 2001, rev. April 2003&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This article is derived from a talk given at the 2001 Franz Developer Symposium.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 1995, my friend Robert Morris and I started a startup called Viaweb. Our plan was to write software that would let end users build online stores. What was novel about this software, at the time, was that it ran on our server, using ordinary Web pages as the interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better Bayesian Filtering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/better/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/better/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;better-bayesian-filtering&#34;&gt;Better Bayesian Filtering&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2003&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This article was given as a talk at the 2003 Spam Conference. It describes the work I&amp;rsquo;ve done to improve the performance of the algorithm described in A Plan for Spam, and what I plan to do in the future.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first discovery I&amp;rsquo;d like to present here is an algorithm for lazy evaluation of research papers. Just write whatever you want and don&amp;rsquo;t cite any previous work, and indignant readers will send you references to all the papers you should have cited. I discovered this algorithm after &amp;ldquo;A Plan for Spam&amp;rdquo; [1] was on Slashdot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distraction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/distraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/distraction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/distraction/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;distraction&#34;&gt;Distraction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disconnecting Distraction Note: The strategy described at the end of this essay didn&amp;rsquo;t work. It would work for a while, and then I&amp;rsquo;d gradually find myself using the Internet on my work computer. I&amp;rsquo;m trying other strategies now, but I think this time I&amp;rsquo;ll wait till I&amp;rsquo;m sure they work before writing about them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Procrastination feeds on distractions. Most people find it uncomfortable just to sit and do nothing; you avoid work by doing something else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic Inequality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/ineq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/ineq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/ineq/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;economic-inequality&#34;&gt;Economic Inequality&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2016&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the 1970s, economic inequality in the US has increased dramatically. And in particular, the rich have gotten a lot richer. Nearly everyone who writes about the topic says that economic inequality should be decreased.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m interested in this question because I was one of the founders of a company called Y Combinator that helps people start startups. Almost by definition, if a startup succeeds, its founders become rich. Which means by helping startup founders I&amp;rsquo;ve been helping to increase economic inequality. If economic inequality should be decreased, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be helping founders. No one should be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fierce Nerds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/fn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/fn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/fn/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;fierce-nerds&#34;&gt;Fierce Nerds&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most people think of nerds as quiet, diffident people. In ordinary social situations they are — as quiet and diffident as the star quarterback would be if he found himself in the middle of a physics symposium. And for the same reason: they are fish out of water. But the apparent diffidence of nerds is an illusion due to the fact that when non-nerds observe them, it&amp;rsquo;s usually in ordinary social situations. In fact some nerds are quite fierce.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filters that Fight Back</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/ffb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/ffb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/ffb/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;filters-that-fight-back&#34;&gt;Filters that Fight Back&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2003&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We may be able to improve the accuracy of Bayesian spam filters by having them follow links to see what&amp;rsquo;s waiting at the other end. Richard Jowsey of death2spam now does this in borderline cases, and reports that it works well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why only do it in borderline cases? And why only do it once?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in Will Filters Kill Spam?, following all the urls in a spam would have an amusing side-effect. If popular email clients did this in order to filter spam, the spammer&amp;rsquo;s servers would take a serious pounding. The more I think about this, the better an idea it seems. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just amusing; it would be hard to imagine a more perfectly targeted counterattack on spammers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Questions about Language Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/langdes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/langdes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/langdes/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;five-questions-about-language-design&#34;&gt;Five Questions about Language Design&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2001&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These are some notes I made for a panel discussion on programming language design at MIT on May 10, 2001.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-programming-languages-are-for-people&#34;&gt;1. Programming Languages Are for People.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Programming languages are how people talk to computers. The computer would be just as happy speaking any language that was unambiguous. The reason we have high level languages is because people can&amp;rsquo;t deal with machine language. The point of programming languages is to prevent our poor frail human brains from being overwhelmed by a mass of detail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Great Hackers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/gh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/gh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/gh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;great-hackers&#34;&gt;Great Hackers&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at Oscon 2004.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I finished a new book, and in reviews I keep noticing words like &amp;ldquo;provocative&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; and &amp;ldquo;controversial.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; To say nothing of &amp;ldquo;idiotic.&#39;&#39;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t mean to make the book controversial. I was trying to make it efficient. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to waste people&amp;rsquo;s time telling them things they already knew. It&amp;rsquo;s more efficient just to give them the diffs. But I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s bound to yield an alarming book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How People Get Rich Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/richnow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/richnow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/richnow/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-people-get-rich-now&#34;&gt;How People Get Rich Now&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every year since 1982, Forbes magazine has published a list of the richest Americans. If we compare the 100 richest people in 1982 to the 100 richest in 2020, we notice some big differences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1982 the most common source of wealth was inheritance. Of the 100 richest people, 60 inherited from an ancestor. There were 10 du Pont heirs alone. By 2020 the number of heirs had been cut in half, accounting for only 27 of the biggest 100 fortunes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Wealth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/wealth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/wealth/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-make-wealth&#34;&gt;How to Make Wealth&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay was originally published in &lt;em&gt;Hackers &amp;amp; Painters&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you wanted to get rich, how would you do it? I think your best bet would be to start or join a startup. That&amp;rsquo;s been a reliable way to get rich for hundreds of years. The word &amp;ldquo;startup&amp;rdquo; dates from the 1960s, but what happens in one is very similar to the venture-backed trading voyages of the Middle Ages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Start a Startup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/start/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-start-a-startup&#34;&gt;How to Start a Startup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at the Harvard Computer Society.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You need three things to create a successful startup: to start with good people, to make something customers actually want, and to spend as little money as possible. Most startups that fail do it because they fail at one of these. A startup that does all three will probably succeed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Lisp is So Great</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/iflisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/iflisp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/iflisp/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;if-lisp-is-so-great&#34;&gt;If Lisp is So Great&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2003&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If Lisp is so great, why don&amp;rsquo;t more people use it? I was asked this question by a student in the audience at a talk I gave recently. Not for the first time, either.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In languages, as in so many things, there&amp;rsquo;s not much correlation between popularity and quality. Why does John Grisham (King of Torts sales rank, 44) outsell Jane Austen (Pride and Prejudice sales rank, 6191)? Would even Grisham claim that it&amp;rsquo;s because he&amp;rsquo;s a better writer?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to ANSI Common Lisp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/acl1txtt1748944359/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/acl1txtt1748944359/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/acl1txtt1748944359/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-to-ansi-common-lisp&#34;&gt;Introduction to ANSI Common Lisp&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction to ANSI Common Lisp&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This is the first chapter of ANSI Common Lisp, by Paul Graham. Copyright 1995, Prentice-Hall.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John McCarthy and his students began work on the first Lisp implementation in 1958. After Fortran, Lisp is the oldest language still in use. [1] What&amp;rsquo;s more remarkable is that it is still in the forefront of programming language technology. Programmers who know Lisp will tell you, there is something about this language that sets it apart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java&#39;s Cover</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/javacover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/javacover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/javacover/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;javas-cover&#34;&gt;Java&amp;rsquo;s Cover&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2001&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This essay developed out of conversations I&amp;rsquo;ve had with several other programmers about why Java smelled suspicious. It&amp;rsquo;s not a critique of Java! It is a case study of hacker&amp;rsquo;s radar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over time, hackers develop a nose for good (and bad) technology. I thought it might be interesting to try and write down what made Java seem suspect to me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some people who&amp;rsquo;ve read this think it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting attempt to write about something that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been written about before. Others say I will get in trouble for appearing to be writing about things I don&amp;rsquo;t understand. So, just in case it does any good, let me clarify that I&amp;rsquo;m not writing here about Java (which I have never used) but about hacker&amp;rsquo;s radar (which I have thought about a lot).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let the Other 95% of Great Programmers In</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/95/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/95/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/95/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;let-the-other-95-of-great-programmers-in&#34;&gt;Let the Other 95% of Great Programmers In&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let the Other 95% of Great Programmers In December 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;American technology companies want the government to make immigration easier because they say they can&amp;rsquo;t find enough programmers in the US. Anti-immigration people say that instead of letting foreigners take these jobs, we should train more Americans to be programmers. Who&amp;rsquo;s right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The technology companies are right. What the anti-immigration people don&amp;rsquo;t understand is that there is a huge variation in ability between competent programmers and exceptional ones, and while you can train people to be competent, you can&amp;rsquo;t train them to be exceptional. Exceptional programmers have an aptitude for and interest in programming that is not merely the product of training. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lisp for Web-Based Applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/lwba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/lwba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lisp-for-web-based-applications&#34;&gt;Lisp for Web-Based Applications&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a link to Beating the Averages was posted on slashdot, some readers wanted to hear in more detail about the specific technical advantages we got from using Lisp in Viaweb. For those who are interested, here are some excerpts from a talk I gave in April 2001 at BBN Labs in Cambridge, MA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BBN Talk Excerpts (ASCII)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft is Dead</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/microsoft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/microsoft/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;microsoft-is-dead&#34;&gt;Microsoft is Dead&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I suddenly realized Microsoft was dead. I was talking to a young startup founder about how Google was different from Yahoo. I said that Yahoo had been warped from the start by their fear of Microsoft. That was why they&amp;rsquo;d positioned themselves as a &amp;ldquo;media company&amp;rdquo; instead of a technology company. Then I looked at his face and realized he didn&amp;rsquo;t understand. It was as if I&amp;rsquo;d told him how much girls liked Barry Manilow in the mid 80s. Barry who? Microsoft? He didn&amp;rsquo;t say anything, but I could tell he didn&amp;rsquo;t quite believe anyone would be frightened of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Gap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/gap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/gap/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;mind-the-gap&#34;&gt;Mind the Gap&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When people care enough about something to do it well, those who do it best tend to be far better than everyone else. There&amp;rsquo;s a huge gap between Leonardo and second-rate contemporaries like Borgognone. You see the same gap between Raymond Chandler and the average writer of detective novels. A top-ranked professional chess player could play ten thousand games against an ordinary club player without losing once.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Property</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/property/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/property/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/property/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;property&#34;&gt;Property&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2012&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a child I read a book of stories about a famous judge in eighteenth century Japan called Ooka Tadasuke. One of the cases he decided was brought by the owner of a food shop. A poor student who could afford only rice was eating his rice while enjoying the delicious cooking smells coming from the food shop. The owner wanted the student to pay for the smells he was enjoying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Return of the Mac</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;return-of-the-mac&#34;&gt;Return of the Mac&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All the best hackers I know are gradually switching to Macs. My friend Robert said his whole research group at MIT recently bought themselves Powerbooks. These guys are not the graphic designers and grandmas who were buying Macs at Apple&amp;rsquo;s low point in the mid 1990s. They&amp;rsquo;re about as hardcore OS hackers as you can get.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason, of course, is OS X. Powerbooks are beautifully designed and run FreeBSD. What more do you need to know?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revenge of the Nerds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/icad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/icad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/icad/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;revenge-of-the-nerds&#34;&gt;Revenge of the Nerds&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2002&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We were after the C++ programmers. We managed to drag a lot of them about halfway to Lisp.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Guy Steele, co-author of the Java spec&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the software business there is an ongoing struggle between the pointy-headed academics, and another equally formidable force, the pointy-haired bosses. Everyone knows who the pointy-haired boss is, right? I think most people in the technology world not only recognize this cartoon character, but know the actual person in their company that he is modelled upon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot: Viaweb, June 1998</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/vw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/vw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/vw/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;snapshot-viaweb-june-1998&#34;&gt;Snapshot: Viaweb, June 1998&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2012&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few hours before the Yahoo acquisition was announced in June 1998 I took a snapshot of Viaweb&amp;rsquo;s site. I thought it might be interesting to look at one day.The first thing one notices is is how tiny the pages are. Screens were a lot smaller in 1998. If I remember correctly, our frontpage used to just fit in the size window people typically used then.Browsers then (IE 6 was still 3 years in the future) had few fonts and they weren&amp;rsquo;t antialiased. If you wanted to make pages that looked good, you had to render display text as images.You may notice a certain similarity between the Viaweb and Y Combinator logos. We did that as an inside joke when we started YC. Considering how basic a red circle is, it seemed surprising to me when we started Viaweb how few other companies used one as their logo. A bit later I realized why.On the Company page you&amp;rsquo;ll notice a mysterious individual called John McArtyem. Robert Morris (aka Rtm) was so publicity averse after the Worm that he didn&amp;rsquo;t want his name on the site. I managed to get him to agree to a compromise: we could use his bio but not his name. He has since relaxed a bit on that point.Trevor graduated at about the same time the acquisition closed, so in the course of 4 days he went from impecunious grad student to millionaire PhD. The culmination of my career as a writer of press releases was one celebrating his graduation, illustrated with a drawing I did of him during a meeting.(Trevor also appears as Trevino Bagwell in our directory of web designers merchants could hire to build stores for them. We inserted him as a ringer in case some competitor tried to spam our web designers. We assumed his logo would deter any actual customers, but it did not.)Back in the 90s, to get users you had to get mentioned in magazines and newspapers. There were not the same ways to get found online that there are today. So we used to pay a PR firm $16,000 a month to get us mentioned in the press. Fortunately reporters liked us.In our advice about getting traffic from search engines (I don&#39;t think the term SEO had been coined yet), we say there are only 7 that matter: Yahoo, AltaVista, Excite, WebCrawler, InfoSeek, Lycos, and HotBot. Notice anything missing? Google was incorporated that September.We supported online transactions via a company called Cybercash, since if we lacked that feature we&#39;d have gotten beaten up in product comparisons. But Cybercash was so bad and most stores&#39; order volumes were so low that it was better if merchants processed orders like phone orders. We had a page in our site trying to talk merchants out of doing real time authorizations.The whole site was organized like a funnel, directing people to the test drive. It was a novel thing to be able to try out software online. We put cgi-bin in our dynamic urls to fool competitors about how our software worked.We had some well known users. Needless to say, Frederick&#39;s of Hollywood got the most traffic. We charged a flat fee of $300/month for big stores, so it was a little alarming to have users who got lots of traffic. I once calculated how much Frederick&amp;rsquo;s was costing us in bandwidth, and it was about $300/month.Since we hosted all the stores, which together were getting just over 10 million page views per month in June 1998, we consumed what at the time seemed a lot of bandwidth. We had 2 T1s (3 Mb/sec) coming into our offices. In those days there was no AWS. Even colocating servers seemed too risky, considering how often things went wrong with them. So we had our servers in our offices. Or more precisely, in Trevor&amp;rsquo;s office. In return for the unique privilege of sharing his office with no other humans, he had to share it with 6 shrieking tower servers. His office was nicknamed the Hot Tub on account of the heat they generated. Most days his stack of window air conditioners could keep up.For describing pages, we had a template language called RTML, which supposedly stood for something, but which in fact I named after Rtm. RTML was Common Lisp augmented by some macros and libraries, and concealed under a structure editor that made it look like it had syntax.Since we did continuous releases, our software didn&amp;rsquo;t actually have versions. But in those days the trade press expected versions, so we made them up. If we wanted to get lots of attention, we made the version number an integer. That &amp;ldquo;version 4.0&amp;rdquo; icon was generated by our own button generator, incidentally. The whole Viaweb site was made with our software, even though it wasn&amp;rsquo;t an online store, because we wanted to experience what our users did.At the end of 1997, we released a general purpose shopping search engine called Shopfind. It was pretty advanced for the time. It had a programmable crawler that could crawl most of the different stores online and pick out the products.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Web Startups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/webstartups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/webstartups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/webstartups/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-future-of-web-startups&#34;&gt;The Future of Web Startups&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a keynote at FOWA in October 2007.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something interesting happening right now. Startups are undergoing the same transformation that technology does when it becomes cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a pattern we see over and over in technology. Initially there&amp;rsquo;s some device that&amp;rsquo;s very expensive and made in small quantities. Then someone discovers how to make them cheaply; many more get built; and as a result they can be used in new ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The High-Res Society</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/highres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/highres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/highres/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-high-res-society&#34;&gt;The High-Res Society&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For nearly all of history the success of a society was proportionate to its ability to assemble large and disciplined organizations. Those who bet on economies of scale generally won, which meant the largest organizations were the most successful ones.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Things have already changed so much that this is hard for us to believe, but till just a few decades ago the largest organizations tended to be the most progressive. An ambitious kid graduating from college in 1960 wanted to work in the huge, gleaming offices of Ford, or General Electric, or NASA. Small meant small-time. Small in 1960 didn&amp;rsquo;t mean a cool little startup. It meant uncle Sid&amp;rsquo;s shoe store.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Other Road Ahead</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/road/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/road/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-other-road-ahead&#34;&gt;The Other Road Ahead&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2001&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This article explains why much of the next generation of software may be server-based, what that will mean for programmers, and why this new kind of software is a great opportunity for startups. It&amp;rsquo;s derived from a talk at BBN Labs.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 1995, my friend Robert Morris and I decided to start a startup. The PR campaign leading up to Netscape&amp;rsquo;s IPO was running full blast then, and there was a lot of talk in the press about online commerce. At the time there might have been thirty actual stores on the Web, all made by hand. If there were going to be a lot of online stores, there would need to be software for making them, so we decided to write some.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of the Marginal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/marginal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/marginal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-power-of-the-marginal&#34;&gt;The Power of the Marginal&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;June 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from talks at Usenix 2006 and Railsconf 2006.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago my friend Trevor and I went to look at the Apple garage. As we stood there, he said that as a kid growing up in Saskatchewan he&amp;rsquo;d been amazed at the dedication Jobs and Wozniak must have had to work in a garage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those guys must have been freezing!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Python Paradox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/pypar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/pypar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-python-paradox&#34;&gt;The Python Paradox&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a recent talk I said something that upset a lot of people: that you could get smarter programmers to work on a Python project than you could to work on a Java project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t mean by this that Java programmers are dumb. I meant that Python programmers are smart. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of work to learn a new programming language. And people don&amp;rsquo;t learn Python because it will get them a job; they learn it because they genuinely like to program and aren&amp;rsquo;t satisfied with the languages they already know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Reddits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/reddits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/reddits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/reddits/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-reddits&#34;&gt;The Reddits&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I met the Reddits before we even started Y Combinator. In fact they were one of the reasons we started it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;YC grew out of a talk I gave to the Harvard Computer Society (the undergrad computer club) about how to start a startup. Everyone else in the audience was probably local, but Steve and Alexis came up on the train from the University of Virginia, where they were seniors. Since they&amp;rsquo;d come so far I agreed to meet them for coffee. They told me about the startup idea we&amp;rsquo;d later fund them to drop: a way to order fast food on your cellphone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trouble with the Segway</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/segway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/segway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/segway/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-trouble-with-the-segway&#34;&gt;The Trouble with the Segway&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Segway hasn&amp;rsquo;t delivered on its initial promise, to put it mildly. There are several reasons why, but one is that people don&amp;rsquo;t want to be seen riding them. Someone riding a Segway looks like a dork.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My friend Trevor Blackwell built his own Segway, which we called the Segwell. He also built a one-wheeled version, the Eunicycle, which looks exactly like a regular unicycle till you realize the rider isn&amp;rsquo;t pedaling. He has ridden them both to downtown Mountain View to get coffee. When he rides the Eunicycle, people smile at him. But when he rides the Segwell, they shout abuse from their cars: &amp;ldquo;Too lazy to walk, ya fuckin homo?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Venture Capital Squeeze</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/vcsqueeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/vcsqueeze/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/vcsqueeze/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-venture-capital-squeeze&#34;&gt;The Venture Capital Squeeze&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the next few years, venture capital funds will find themselves squeezed from four directions. They&amp;rsquo;re already stuck with a seller&amp;rsquo;s market, because of the huge amounts they raised at the end of the Bubble and still haven&amp;rsquo;t invested. This by itself is not the end of the world. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s just a more extreme version of the norm in the VC business: too much money chasing too few deals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Word &#39;Hacker&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/gba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/gba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/gba/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-word-hacker&#34;&gt;The Word &amp;ldquo;Hacker&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To the popular press, &amp;ldquo;hacker&amp;rdquo; means someone who breaks into computers. Among programmers it means a good programmer. But the two meanings are connected. To programmers, &amp;ldquo;hacker&amp;rdquo; connotes mastery in the most literal sense: someone who can make a computer do what he wants—whether the computer wants to or not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To add to the confusion, the noun &amp;ldquo;hack&amp;rdquo; also has two senses. It can be either a compliment or an insult. It&amp;rsquo;s called a hack when you do something in an ugly way. But when you do something so clever that you somehow beat the system, that&amp;rsquo;s also called a hack. The word is used more often in the former than the latter sense, probably because ugly solutions are more common than brilliant ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web 2.0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/web20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/web20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/web20/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;web-20&#34;&gt;Web 2.0&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does &amp;ldquo;Web 2.0&amp;rdquo; mean anything? Till recently I thought it didn&amp;rsquo;t, but the truth turns out to be more complicated. Originally, yes, it was meaningless. Now it seems to have acquired a meaning. And yet those who dislike the term are probably right, because if it means what I think it does, we don&amp;rsquo;t need it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I first heard the phrase &amp;ldquo;Web 2.0&amp;rdquo; in the name of the Web 2.0 conference in 2004. At the time it was supposed to mean using &amp;ldquo;the web as a platform,&amp;rdquo; which I took to refer to web-based applications. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weird Languages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/weird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/weird/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;weird-languages&#34;&gt;Weird Languages&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When people say that in their experience all programming languages are basically equivalent, they&amp;rsquo;re making a statement not about languages but about the kind of programming they&amp;rsquo;ve done.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99.5% of programming consists of gluing together calls to library functions. All popular languages are equally good at this. So one can easily spend one&amp;rsquo;s whole career operating in the intersection of popular programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But the other .5% of programming is disproportionately interesting. If you want to learn what it consists of, the weirdness of weird languages is a good clue to follow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Lisp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/acl2txtt1748944359/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/acl2txtt1748944359/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/acl2txtt1748944359/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-lisp&#34;&gt;Welcome to Lisp&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter aims to get you programming as soon as possible. By the end of it you will know enough Common Lisp to begin writing programs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;21-form&#34;&gt;2.1 Form&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is particularly true of Lisp that you learn it by using it, because Lisp is an interactive language. Any Lisp system will include an interactive front-end called the toplevel. You type Lisp expressions into the toplevel, and the system displays their values. Lisp usually displays a prompt to tell you that it&amp;rsquo;s waiting for you to type something. Many implementations of Common Lisp use &amp;gt; as the toplevel prompt. That&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;ll use here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Happened to Yahoo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/yahoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/yahoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/yahoo/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-happened-to-yahoo&#34;&gt;What Happened to Yahoo&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2010When I went to work for Yahoo after they bought our startup in 1998, it felt like the center of the world. It was supposed to be the next big thing. It was supposed to be what Google turned out to be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What went wrong? The problems that hosed Yahoo go back a long time, practically to the beginning of the company. They were already very visible when I got there in 1998. Yahoo had two problems Google didn&amp;rsquo;t: easy money, and ambivalence about being a technology company.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Languages Fix</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/fix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/fix/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-languages-fix&#34;&gt;What Languages Fix&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kevin Kelleher suggested an interesting way to compare programming languages: to describe each in terms of the problem it fixes. The surprising thing is how many, and how well, languages can be described this way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Algol: Assembly language is too low-level.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pascal: Algol doesn&amp;rsquo;t have enough data types.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modula: Pascal is too wimpy for systems programming.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simula: Algol isn&amp;rsquo;t good enough at simulations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Smalltalk: Not everything in Simula is an object.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Made Lisp Different</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/diff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/diff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/diff/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-made-lisp-different&#34;&gt;What Made Lisp Different&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2001 (rev. May 2002)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This article came about in response to some questions on the LL1 mailing list. It is now incorporated in Revenge of the Nerds.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When McCarthy designed Lisp in the late 1950s, it was a radical departure from existing languages, the most important of which was Fortran.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lisp embodied nine new ideas:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conditionals.&lt;/strong&gt; A conditional is an if-then-else construct. We take these for granted now. They were invented by McCarthy in the course of developing Lisp. (Fortran at that time only had a conditional goto, closely based on the branch instruction in the underlying hardware.) McCarthy, who was on the Algol committee, got conditionals into Algol, whence they spread to most other languages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the Bubble Got Right</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/bubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/bubble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/bubble/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-the-bubble-got-right&#34;&gt;What the Bubble Got Right&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from an invited talk at ICFP 2004.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had a front row seat for the Internet Bubble, because I worked at Yahoo during 1998 and 1999. One day, when the stock was trading around $200, I sat down and calculated what I thought the price should be. The answer I got was $12. I went to the next cubicle and told my friend Trevor. &amp;ldquo;Twelve!&amp;rdquo; he said. He tried to sound indignant, but he didn&amp;rsquo;t quite manage it. He knew as well as I did that our valuation was crazy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why to Start a Startup in a Bad Economy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/badeconomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/badeconomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/badeconomy/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-to-start-a-startup-in-a-bad-economy&#34;&gt;Why to Start a Startup in a Bad Economy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The economic situation is apparently so grim that some experts fear we may be in for a stretch as bad as the mid seventies. When Microsoft and Apple were founded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As those examples suggest, a recession may not be such a bad time to start a startup. I&amp;rsquo;m not claiming it&amp;rsquo;s a particularly good time either. The truth is more boring: the state of the economy doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter much either way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why TV Lost</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/convergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/convergence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/convergence/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-tv-lost&#34;&gt;Why TV Lost&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About twenty years ago people noticed computers and TV were on a collision course and started to speculate about what they&amp;rsquo;d produce when they converged. We now know the answer: computers. It&amp;rsquo;s clear now that even by using the word &amp;ldquo;convergence&amp;rdquo; we were giving TV too much credit. This won&amp;rsquo;t be convergence so much as replacement. People may still watch things they call &amp;ldquo;TV shows,&amp;rdquo; but they&amp;rsquo;ll watch them mostly on computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writes and Write-Nots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/writes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/writes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/writes/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;writes-and-write-nots&#34;&gt;Writes and Write-Nots&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m usually reluctant to make predictions about technology, but I feel fairly confident about this one: in a couple decades there won&amp;rsquo;t be many people who can write.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the strangest things you learn if you&amp;rsquo;re a writer is how many people have trouble writing. Doctors know how many people have a mole they&amp;rsquo;re worried about; people who are good at setting up computers know how many people aren&amp;rsquo;t; writers know how many people need help writing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
