<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Charity on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/charity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Charity on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/charity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An NFT That Saves Lives</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/nft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/nft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/nft/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-nft-that-saves-lives&#34;&gt;An NFT That Saves Lives&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Noora Health, a nonprofit I&amp;rsquo;ve supported for years, just launched a new NFT. It has a dramatic name, Save Thousands of Lives, because that&amp;rsquo;s what the proceeds will do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Noora has been saving lives for 7 years. They run programs in hospitals in South Asia to teach new mothers how to take care of their babies once they get home. They&amp;rsquo;re in 165 hospitals now. And because they know the numbers before and after they start at a new hospital, they can measure the impact they have. It is massive. For every 1000 live births, they save 9 babies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Good</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/good/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/good/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;be-good&#34;&gt;Be Good&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at the 2008 Startup School.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About a month after we started Y Combinator we came up with the phrase that became our motto: Make something people want. We&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot since then, but if I were choosing now that&amp;rsquo;s still the one I&amp;rsquo;d pick.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another thing we tell founders is not to worry too much about the business model, at least at first. Not because making money is unimportant, but because it&amp;rsquo;s so much easier than building something great.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donate Unrestricted</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/donate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/donate/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;donate-unrestricted&#34;&gt;Donate Unrestricted&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The secret curse of the nonprofit world is restricted donations. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t been involved with nonprofits, you may never have heard this phrase before. But if you have been, it probably made you wince.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Restricted donations mean donations where the donor limits what can be done with the money. This is common with big donations, perhaps the default. And yet it&amp;rsquo;s usually a bad idea. Usually the way the donor wants the money spent is not the way the nonprofit would have chosen. Otherwise there would have been no need to restrict the donation. But who has a better understanding of where money needs to be spent, the nonprofit or the donor?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
