<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Startup Hubs on Linguista</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1355/tags/startup-hubs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Startup Hubs on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1355/tags/startup-hubs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Pittsburgh a Startup Hub</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/pgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/pgh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/pgh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-make-pittsburgh-a-startup-hub&#34;&gt;How to Make Pittsburgh a Startup Hub&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2016&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This is a talk I gave at an event called Opt412 in Pittsburgh. Much of it will apply to other towns. But not all, because as I say in the talk, Pittsburgh has some important advantages over most would-be startup hubs.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What would it take to make Pittsburgh into a startup hub, like Silicon Valley? I understand Pittsburgh pretty well, because I grew up here, in Monroeville. And I understand Silicon Valley pretty well because that&amp;rsquo;s where I live now. Could you get that kind of startup ecosystem going here?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Startup Hubs Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/hubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/hubs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/hubs/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-startup-hubs-work&#34;&gt;Why Startup Hubs Work&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2011&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you look at a list of US cities sorted by population, the number of successful startups per capita varies by orders of magnitude. Somehow it&amp;rsquo;s as if most places were sprayed with startupicide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wondered about this for years. I could see the average town was like a roach motel for startup ambitions: smart, ambitious people went in, but no startups came out. But I was never able to figure out exactly what happened inside the motel—exactly what was killing all the potential startups. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why to Move to a Startup Hub</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/startuphubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/startuphubs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/startuphubs/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-to-move-to-a-startup-hub&#34;&gt;Why to Move to a Startup Hub&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the last talk I gave, one of the organizers got up on the stage to deliver an impromptu rebuttal. That never happened before. I only heard the first few sentences, but that was enough to tell what I said that upset him: that startups would do better if they moved to Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This conference was in London, and most of the audience seemed to be from the UK. So saying startups should move to Silicon Valley seemed like a nationalistic remark: an obnoxious American telling them that if they wanted to do things right they should all just move to America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
