<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courage on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/courage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courage on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/courage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>hamming advice</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/hamming-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/hamming-advice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/hamming-advice.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mccurley.org/advice/hamming_advice.html&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;hamming-advice&#34;&gt;Hamming Advice&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Little has been written on managing your own research (and very little on avoiding other people managing your research); however, your research is much more under your control than you may realize.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are concerned with great research here. Work that will get wide recognition, perhaps even win Nobel Prize. As most people realize, the average published paper is read by the author, the referee, and perhaps one other person. Classic papers are read by thousands. We are concerned with research that will matter in the long run and become more than a footnote in history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mod</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/mod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/mod/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mod&#34;&gt;Mod&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-two-kinds-of-moderate&#34;&gt;The Two Kinds of Moderate&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2019&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two distinct ways to be politically moderate: on purpose and by accident. Intentional moderates are trimmers, deliberately choosing a position mid-way between the extremes of right and left. Accidental moderates end up in the middle, on average, because they make up their own minds about each question, and the far right and far left are roughly equally wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can distinguish intentional from accidental moderates by the distribution of their opinions. If the far left opinion on some matter is 0 and the far right opinion 100, an intentional moderate&amp;rsquo;s opinion on every question will be near 50. Whereas an accidental moderate&amp;rsquo;s opinions will be scattered over a broad range, but will, like those of the intentional moderate, average to about 50.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
