<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Startup on Linguage</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/startup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Startup on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Local Revolution?</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/revolution/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-local-revolution&#34;&gt;A Local Revolution?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently I realized I&amp;rsquo;d been holding two ideas in my head that would explode if combined.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first is that startups may represent a new economic phase, on the scale of the Industrial Revolution. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure of this, but there seems a decent chance it&amp;rsquo;s true. People are dramatically more productive as founders or early employees of startups—imagine how much less Larry and Sergey would have achieved if they&amp;rsquo;d gone to work for a big company—and that scale of improvement can change social customs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ace</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/ace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/ace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/ace/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;ace&#34;&gt;Ace&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ace December 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I was deciding what to write about next, I was surprised to find that two separate essays I&amp;rsquo;d been planning to write were actually the same.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first is about how to ace your Y Combinator interview. There has been so much nonsense written about this topic that I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning for years to write something telling founders the truth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second is about something politicians sometimes say — that the only way to become a billionaire is by exploiting people — and why this is mistaken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Airbnb</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/airbnb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/airbnb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/airbnb/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;airbnb&#34;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2011&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Fred Wilson published a remarkable post about missing Airbnb. VCs miss good startups all the time, but it&amp;rsquo;s extraordinarily rare for one to talk about it publicly till long afterward. So that post is further evidence what a rare bird Fred is. He&amp;rsquo;s probably the nicest VC I know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reading Fred&amp;rsquo;s post made me go back and look at the emails I exchanged with him at the time, trying to convince him to invest in Airbnb. It was quite interesting to read. You can see Fred&amp;rsquo;s mind at work as he circles the deal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Alternative Theory of Unions</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/unions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/unions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/unions/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-alternative-theory-of-unions&#34;&gt;An Alternative Theory of Unions&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People who worry about the increasing gap between rich and poor generally look back on the mid twentieth century as a golden age. In those days we had a large number of high-paying union manufacturing jobs that boosted the median income. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t quite call the high-paying union job a myth, but I think people who dwell on it are reading too much into it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Before the Startup</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/before/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/before/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/before/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;before-the-startup&#34;&gt;Before the Startup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a guest lecture in Sam Altman&amp;rsquo;s startup class at Stanford. It&amp;rsquo;s intended for college students, but much of it is applicable to potential founders at other ages.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the advantages of having kids is that when you have to give advice, you can ask yourself &amp;ldquo;what would I tell my own kids?&amp;rdquo; My kids are little, but I can imagine what I&amp;rsquo;d tell them about startups if they were in college, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change Your Name</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/name/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/name/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/name/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;change-your-name&#34;&gt;Change Your Name&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2015&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have a US startup called X and you don&amp;rsquo;t have x.com, you should probably change your name.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason is not just that people can&amp;rsquo;t find you. For companies with mobile apps, especially, having the right domain name is not as critical as it used to be for getting users. The problem with not having the .com of your name is that it signals weakness. Unless you&amp;rsquo;re so big that your reputation precedes you, a marginal domain suggests you&amp;rsquo;re a marginal company. Whereas (as Stripe shows) having x.com signals strength even if it has no relation to what you do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Default Alive or Default Dead?</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/aord/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/aord/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/aord/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;default-alive-or-default-dead&#34;&gt;Default Alive or Default Dead?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2015&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I talk to a startup that&amp;rsquo;s been operating for more than 8 or 9 months, the first thing I want to know is almost always the same. Assuming their expenses remain constant and their revenue growth is what it has been over the last several months, do they make it to profitability on the money they have left? Or to put it more dramatically, by default do they live or die?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Founders</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/5founders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/5founders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/5founders/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;five-founders&#34;&gt;Five Founders&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Five Founders April 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inc recently asked me who I thought were the 5 most interesting startup founders of the last 30 years. How do you decide who&amp;rsquo;s the most interesting? The best test seemed to be influence: who are the 5 who&amp;rsquo;ve influenced me most? Who do I use as examples when I&amp;rsquo;m talking to companies we fund? Who do I find myself quoting?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d guess Steve is the most influential founder not just for me but for most people you could ask. A lot of startup culture is Apple culture. He was the original young founder. And while the concept of &amp;ldquo;insanely great&amp;rdquo; already existed in the arts, it was a novel idea to introduce into a company in the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frighteningly Ambitious Startup Ideas</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/ambitious/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/ambitious/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/ambitious/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;frighteningly-ambitious-startup-ideas&#34;&gt;Frighteningly Ambitious Startup Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2012&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the more surprising things I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed while working on Y Combinator is how frightening the most ambitious startup ideas are. In this essay I&amp;rsquo;m going to demonstrate this phenomenon by describing some. Any one of them could make you a billionaire. That might sound like an attractive prospect, and yet when I describe these ideas you may notice you find yourself shrinking away from them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How People Get Rich Now</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/richnow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/richnow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/richnow/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-people-get-rich-now&#34;&gt;How People Get Rich Now&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every year since 1982, Forbes magazine has published a list of the richest Americans. If we compare the 100 richest people in 1982 to the 100 richest in 2020, we notice some big differences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1982 the most common source of wealth was inheritance. Of the 100 richest people, 60 inherited from an ancestor. There were 10 du Pont heirs alone. By 2020 the number of heirs had been cut in half, accounting for only 27 of the biggest 100 fortunes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Be an Angel Investor</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/angelinvesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/angelinvesting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/angelinvesting/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-be-an-angel-investor&#34;&gt;How to Be an Angel Investor&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at AngelConf.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we sold our startup in 1998 I thought one day I&amp;rsquo;d do some angel investing. Seven years later I still hadn&amp;rsquo;t started. I put it off because it seemed mysterious and complicated. It turns out to be easier than I expected, and also more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The part I thought was hard, the mechanics of investing, really isn&amp;rsquo;t. You give a startup money and they give you stock. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably get either preferred stock, which means stock with extra rights like getting your money back first in a sale, or convertible debt, which means (on paper) you&amp;rsquo;re lending the company money, and the debt converts to stock at the next sufficiently big funding round. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Convince Investors</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/convince/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/convince/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/convince/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-convince-investors&#34;&gt;How to Convince Investors&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2013&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When people hurt themselves lifting heavy things, it&amp;rsquo;s usually because they try to lift with their back. The right way to lift heavy things is to let your legs do the work. Inexperienced founders make the same mistake when trying to convince investors. They try to convince with their pitch. Most would be better off if they let their startup do the work—if they started by understanding why their startup is worth investing in, then simply explained this well to investors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maker&#39;s Schedule, Manager&#39;s Schedule</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/makersschedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/makersschedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;makers-schedule-managers-schedule&#34;&gt;Maker&amp;rsquo;s Schedule, Manager&amp;rsquo;s Schedule&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;the mere consciousness of an engagement will sometimes worry a whole day.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;– Charles Dickens&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One reason programmers dislike meetings so much is that they&amp;rsquo;re on a different type of schedule from other people. Meetings cost them more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two types of schedule, which I&amp;rsquo;ll call the manager&amp;rsquo;s schedule and the maker&amp;rsquo;s schedule. The manager&amp;rsquo;s schedule is for bosses. It&amp;rsquo;s embodied in the traditional appointment book, with each day cut into one hour intervals. You can block off several hours for a single task if you need to, but by default you change what you&amp;rsquo;re doing every hour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ramen Profitable</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/ramenprofitable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/ramenprofitable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/ramenprofitable/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;ramen-profitable&#34;&gt;Ramen Profitable&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that the term &amp;ldquo;ramen profitable&amp;rdquo; has become widespread, I ought to explain precisely what the idea entails.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ramen profitable means a startup makes just enough to pay the founders&amp;rsquo; living expenses. This is a different form of profitability than startups have traditionally aimed for. Traditional profitability means a big bet is finally paying off, whereas the main importance of ramen profitability is that it buys you time. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relentlessly Resourceful</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/relres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/relres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/relres/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;relentlessly-resourceful&#34;&gt;Relentlessly Resourceful&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago I finally got being a good startup founder down to two words: relentlessly resourceful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Till then the best I&amp;rsquo;d managed was to get the opposite quality down to one: hapless. Most dictionaries say hapless means unlucky. But the dictionaries are not doing a very good job. A team that outplays its opponents but loses because of a bad decision by the referee could be called unlucky, but not hapless. Hapless implies passivity. To be hapless is to be battered by circumstances — to let the world have its way with you, instead of having your way with the world. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schlep Blindness</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/schlep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/schlep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/schlep/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;schlep-blindness&#34;&gt;Schlep Blindness&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2012&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are great startup ideas lying around unexploited right under our noses. One reason we don&amp;rsquo;t see them is a phenomenon I call schlep blindness. Schlep was originally a Yiddish word but has passed into general use in the US. It means a tedious, unpleasant task.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No one likes schleps, but hackers especially dislike them. Most hackers who start startups wish they could do it by just writing some clever software, putting it on a server somewhere, and watching the money roll in—without ever having to talk to users, or negotiate with other companies, or deal with other people&amp;rsquo;s broken code. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s possible, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startups in 13 Sentences</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/13sentences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/13sentences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/13sentences/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;startups-in-13-sentences&#34;&gt;Startups in 13 Sentences&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator. Watch how this essay was written. February 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the things I always tell startups is a principle I learned from Paul Buchheit: it&amp;rsquo;s better to make a few people really happy than to make a lot of people semi-happy. I was saying recently to a reporter that if I could only tell startups 10 things, this would be one of them. Then I thought: what would the other 9 be?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Airbnbs</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/airbnbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/airbnbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/airbnbs/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-airbnbs&#34;&gt;The Airbnbs&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To celebrate Airbnb&amp;rsquo;s IPO and to help future founders, I thought it might be useful to explain what was special about Airbnb.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What was special about the Airbnbs was how earnest they were. They did nothing half-way, and we could sense this even in the interview. Sometimes after we interviewed a startup we&amp;rsquo;d be uncertain what to do, and have to talk it over. Other times we&amp;rsquo;d just look at one another and smile. The Airbnbs&amp;rsquo; interview was that kind. We didn&amp;rsquo;t even like the idea that much. Nor did users, at that stage; they had no growth. But the founders seemed so full of energy that it was impossible not to like them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lesson to Unlearn</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/lesson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/lesson/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-lesson-to-unlearn&#34;&gt;The Lesson to Unlearn&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2019&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most damaging thing you learned in school wasn&amp;rsquo;t something you learned in any specific class. It was learning to get good grades.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was in college, a particularly earnest philosophy grad student once told me that he never cared what grade he got in a class, only what he learned in it. This stuck in my mind because it was the only time I ever heard anyone say such a thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Other Half of &#39;Artists Ship&#39;</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/artistsship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/artistsship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/artistsship/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-other-half-of-artists-ship&#34;&gt;The Other Half of &amp;ldquo;Artists Ship&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the differences between big companies and startups is that big companies tend to have developed procedures to protect themselves against mistakes. A startup walks like a toddler, bashing into things and falling over all the time. A big company is more deliberate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The gradual accumulation of checks in an organization is a kind of learning, based on disasters that have happened to it or others like it. After giving a contract to a supplier who goes bankrupt and fails to deliver, for example, a company might require all suppliers to prove they&amp;rsquo;re solvent before submitting bids.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of the Marginal</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/marginal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/marginal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-power-of-the-marginal&#34;&gt;The Power of the Marginal&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;June 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from talks at Usenix 2006 and Railsconf 2006.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago my friend Trevor and I went to look at the Apple garage. As we stood there, he said that as a kid growing up in Saskatchewan he&amp;rsquo;d been amazed at the dedication Jobs and Wozniak must have had to work in a garage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those guys must have been freezing!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Reddits</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/reddits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/reddits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/reddits/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-reddits&#34;&gt;The Reddits&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I met the Reddits before we even started Y Combinator. In fact they were one of the reasons we started it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;YC grew out of a talk I gave to the Harvard Computer Society (the undergrad computer club) about how to start a startup. Everyone else in the audience was probably local, but Steve and Alexis came up on the train from the University of Virginia, where they were seniors. Since they&amp;rsquo;d come so far I agreed to meet them for coffee. They told me about the startup idea we&amp;rsquo;d later fund them to drop: a way to order fast food on your cellphone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Top Idea in Your Mind</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/top/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/top/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/top/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-top-idea-in-your-mind&#34;&gt;The Top Idea in Your Mind&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2010&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I realized recently that what one thinks about in the shower in the morning is more important than I&amp;rsquo;d thought. I knew it was a good time to have ideas. Now I&amp;rsquo;d go further: now I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s hard to do a really good job on anything you don&amp;rsquo;t think about in the shower.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everyone who&amp;rsquo;s worked on difficult problems is probably familiar with the phenomenon of working hard to figure something out, failing, and then suddenly seeing the answer a bit later while doing something else. There&amp;rsquo;s a kind of thinking you do without trying to. I&amp;rsquo;m increasingly convinced this type of thinking is not merely helpful in solving hard problems, but necessary. The tricky part is, you can only control it indirectly. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web 2.0</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/web20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/web20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/web20/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;web-20&#34;&gt;Web 2.0&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does &amp;ldquo;Web 2.0&amp;rdquo; mean anything? Till recently I thought it didn&amp;rsquo;t, but the truth turns out to be more complicated. Originally, yes, it was meaningless. Now it seems to have acquired a meaning. And yet those who dislike the term are probably right, because if it means what I think it does, we don&amp;rsquo;t need it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I first heard the phrase &amp;ldquo;Web 2.0&amp;rdquo; in the name of the Web 2.0 conference in 2004. At the time it was supposed to mean using &amp;ldquo;the web as a platform,&amp;rdquo; which I took to refer to web-based applications. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve Learned from Users</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/users/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-ive-learned-from-users&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve Learned from Users&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently told applicants to Y Combinator that the best advice I could give for getting in, per word, was &amp;ldquo;Explain what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned from users.&amp;rdquo; That tests a lot of things: whether you&amp;rsquo;re paying attention to users, how well you understand them, and even how much they need what you&amp;rsquo;re making.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Afterward I asked myself the same question. What have I learned from YC&amp;rsquo;s users, the startups we&amp;rsquo;ve funded?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Microsoft Is this the Altair Basic of?</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/altair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/altair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/altair/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-microsoft-is-this-the-altair-basic-of&#34;&gt;What Microsoft Is this the Altair Basic of?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;February 2015&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most valuable exercises you can try if you want to understand startups is to look at the most successful companies and explain why they were not as lame as they seemed when they first launched. Because they practically all seemed lame at first. Not just small, lame. Not just the first step up a big mountain. More like the first step into a swamp.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Startups Are Really Like</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/really/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/really/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-startups-are-really-like&#34;&gt;What Startups Are Really Like&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at the 2009 Startup School.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what to talk about at Startup School, so I decided to ask the founders of the startups we&amp;rsquo;d funded. What hadn&amp;rsquo;t I written about yet?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in the unusual position of being able to test the essays I write about startups. I hope the ones on other topics are right, but I have no way to test them. The ones on startups get tested by about 70 people every 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When To Do What You Love</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/when/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/when/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/when/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-to-do-what-you-love&#34;&gt;When To Do What You Love&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some debate about whether it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to &amp;ldquo;follow your passion.&amp;rdquo; In fact the question is impossible to answer with a simple yes or no. Sometimes you should and sometimes you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t, but the border between should and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t is very complicated. The only way to give a general answer is to trace it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When people talk about this question, there&amp;rsquo;s always an implicit &amp;ldquo;instead of.&amp;rdquo; All other things being equal, why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you work on what interests you the most? So even raising the question implies that all other things aren&amp;rsquo;t equal, and that you have to choose between working on what interests you the most and something else, like what pays the best.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Startups Condense in America</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/america/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/america/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-startups-condense-in-america&#34;&gt;Why Startups Condense in America&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a keynote at Xtech.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Startups happen in clusters. There are a lot of them in Silicon Valley and Boston, and few in Chicago or Miami. A country that wants startups will probably also have to reproduce whatever makes these clusters form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve claimed that the recipe is a great university near a town smart people like. If you set up those conditions within the US, startups will form as inevitably as water droplets condense on a cold piece of metal. But when I consider what it would take to reproduce Silicon Valley in another country, it&amp;rsquo;s clear the US is a particularly humid environment. Startups condense more easily here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why to Start a Startup in a Bad Economy</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/badeconomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/badeconomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/badeconomy/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-to-start-a-startup-in-a-bad-economy&#34;&gt;Why to Start a Startup in a Bad Economy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The economic situation is apparently so grim that some experts fear we may be in for a stretch as bad as the mid seventies. When Microsoft and Apple were founded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As those examples suggest, a recession may not be such a bad time to start a startup. I&amp;rsquo;m not claiming it&amp;rsquo;s a particularly good time either. The truth is more boring: the state of the economy doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter much either way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why YC</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/whyyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/whyyc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/whyyc/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-yc&#34;&gt;Why YC&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2006, rev August 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday one of the founders we funded asked me why we started Y Combinator. Or more precisely, he asked if we&amp;rsquo;d started YC mainly for fun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kind of, but not quite. It is enormously fun to be able to work with Rtm and Trevor again. I missed that after we sold Viaweb, and for all the years after I always had a background process running, looking for something we could do together. There is definitely an aspect of a band reunion to Y Combinator. Every couple days I slip and call it &amp;ldquo;Viaweb.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
