<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intelligence on Linguista</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1355/tags/intelligence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intelligence on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1355/tags/intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/alien/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/alien/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/alien/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;alien-truth&#34;&gt;Alien Truth&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If there were intelligent beings elsewhere in the universe, they&amp;rsquo;d share certain truths in common with us. The truths of mathematics would be the same, because they&amp;rsquo;re true by definition. Ditto for the truths of physics; the mass of a carbon atom would be the same on their planet. But I think we&amp;rsquo;d share other truths with aliens besides the truths of math and physics, and that it would be worthwhile to think about what these might be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Smart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/smart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/smart/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;beyond-smart&#34;&gt;Beyond Smart&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you asked people what was special about Einstein, most would say that he was really smart. Even the ones who tried to give you a more sophisticated-sounding answer would probably think this first. Till a few years ago I would have given the same answer myself. But that wasn&amp;rsquo;t what was special about Einstein. What was special about him was that he had important new ideas. Being very smart was a necessary precondition for having those ideas, but the two are not identical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is It Worth Being Wise?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/wisdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/wisdom/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-it-worth-being-wise&#34;&gt;Is It Worth Being Wise?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;February 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I finally figured out something I&amp;rsquo;ve wondered about for 25 years: the relationship between wisdom and intelligence. Anyone can see they&amp;rsquo;re not the same by the number of people who are smart, but not very wise. And yet intelligence and wisdom do seem related. How?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is wisdom? I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s knowing what to do in a lot of situations. I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to make a deep point here about the true nature of wisdom, just to figure out how we use the word. A wise person is someone who usually knows the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Nerds are Unpopular</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/nerds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/nerds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/nerds/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-nerds-are-unpopular&#34;&gt;Why Nerds are Unpopular&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;February 2003&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we were in junior high school, my friend Rich and I made a map of the school lunch tables according to popularity. This was easy to do, because kids only ate lunch with others of about the same popularity. We graded them from A to E. A tables were full of football players and cheerleaders and so on. E tables contained the kids with mild cases of Down&amp;rsquo;s Syndrome, what in the language of the time we called &amp;ldquo;retards.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
