<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Survival on Linguage</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/survival/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Survival on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/survival/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Fundraising Survival Guide</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/fundraising/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/fundraising/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/fundraising/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-fundraising-survival-guide&#34;&gt;A Fundraising Survival Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Raising money is the second hardest part of starting a startup. The hardest part is making something people want: most startups that die, die because they didn&amp;rsquo;t do that. But the second biggest cause of death is probably the difficulty of raising money. Fundraising is brutal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One reason it&amp;rsquo;s so brutal is simply the brutality of markets. People who&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of their lives in schools or big companies may not have been exposed to that. Professors and bosses usually feel some sense of responsibility toward you; if you make a valiant effort and fail, they&amp;rsquo;ll cut you a break. Markets are less forgiving. Customers don&amp;rsquo;t care how hard you worked, only whether you solved their problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Default Alive or Default Dead?</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/aord/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/aord/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/aord/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;default-alive-or-default-dead&#34;&gt;Default Alive or Default Dead?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2015&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I talk to a startup that&amp;rsquo;s been operating for more than 8 or 9 months, the first thing I want to know is almost always the same. Assuming their expenses remain constant and their revenue growth is what it has been over the last several months, do they make it to profitability on the money they have left? Or to put it more dramatically, by default do they live or die?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Not to Die</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/die/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/die/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/die/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-not-to-die&#34;&gt;How Not to Die&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This is a talk I gave at the last Y Combinator dinner of the summer. Usually we don&amp;rsquo;t have a speaker at the last dinner; it&amp;rsquo;s more of a party. But it seemed worth spoiling the atmosphere if I could save some of the startups from preventable deaths. So at the last minute I cooked up this rather grim talk. I didn&amp;rsquo;t mean this as an essay; I wrote it down because I only had two hours before dinner and think fastest while writing.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fatal Pinch</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/pinch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/pinch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/pinch/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-fatal-pinch&#34;&gt;The Fatal Pinch&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many startups go through a point a few months before they die where although they have a significant amount of money in the bank, they&amp;rsquo;re also losing a lot each month, and revenue growth is either nonexistent or mediocre. The company has, say, 6 months of runway. Or to put it more brutally, 6 months before they&amp;rsquo;re out of business. They expect to avoid that by raising more from investors. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
