<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Decision Making on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1366/tags/decision-making/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Decision Making on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1366/tags/decision-making/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Right Kind of Stubborn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/persistence/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-right-kind-of-stubborn&#34;&gt;The Right Kind of Stubborn&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Successful people tend to be persistent. New ideas often don&amp;rsquo;t work at first, but they&amp;rsquo;re not deterred. They keep trying and eventually find something that does.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mere obstinacy, on the other hand, is a recipe for failure. Obstinate people are so annoying. They won&amp;rsquo;t listen. They beat their heads against a wall and get nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But is there any real difference between these two cases? Are persistent and obstinate people actually behaving differently? Or are they doing the same thing, and we just label them later as persistent or obstinate depending on whether they turned out to be right or not?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What You (Want to)* Want</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/want/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/want/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/want/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-you-want-to-want&#34;&gt;What You (Want to)* Want&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since I was about 9 I&amp;rsquo;ve been puzzled by the apparent contradiction between being made of matter that behaves in a predictable way, and the feeling that I could choose to do whatever I wanted. At the time I had a self-interested motive for exploring the question. At that age (like most succeeding ages) I was always in trouble with the authorities, and it seemed to me that there might possibly be some way to get out of trouble by arguing that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t responsible for my actions. I gradually lost hope of that, but the puzzle remained: How do you reconcile being a machine made of matter with the feeling that you&amp;rsquo;re free to choose what you do? [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
