<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analysis on Linguage</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analysis on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cities and Ambition</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/cities/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;cities-and-ambition&#34;&gt;Cities and Ambition&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great cities attract ambitious people. You can sense it when you walk around one. In a hundred subtle ways, the city sends you a message: you could do more; you should try harder.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The surprising thing is how different these messages can be. New York tells you, above all: you should make more money. There are other messages too, of course. You should be hipper. You should be better looking. But the clearest message is that you should be richer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conformism</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/conformism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/conformism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/conformism/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;conformism&#34;&gt;Conformism&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-four-quadrants-of-conformism&#34;&gt;The Four Quadrants of Conformism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most revealing ways to classify people is by the degree and aggressiveness of their conformism. Imagine a Cartesian coordinate system whose horizontal axis runs from conventional-minded on the left to independent-minded on the right, and whose vertical axis runs from passive at the bottom to aggressive at the top. The resulting four quadrants define four types of people. Starting in the upper left and going counter-clockwise: aggressively conventional-minded, passively conventional-minded, passively independent-minded, and aggressively independent-minded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus and Credibility</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/cred/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/cred/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/cred/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;coronavirus-and-credibility&#34;&gt;Coronavirus and Credibility&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a video of TV journalists and politicians confidently saying that the coronavirus would be no worse than the flu. What struck me about it was not just how mistaken they seemed, but how daring. How could they feel safe saying such things?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The answer, I realized, is that they didn&amp;rsquo;t think they could get caught. They didn&amp;rsquo;t realize there was any danger in making false predictions. These people constantly make false predictions, and get away with it, because the things they make predictions about either have mushy enough outcomes that they can bluster their way out of trouble, or happen so far in the future that few remember what they said.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Charisma, Stupid</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/charisma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/charisma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/charisma/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;its-charisma-stupid&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Charisma, Stupid&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2004, corrected June 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor says we should prefer the simpler of two explanations. I begin by reminding readers of this principle because I&amp;rsquo;m about to propose a theory that will offend both liberals and conservatives. But Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor means, in effect, that if you want to disagree with it, you have a hell of a coincidence to explain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theory: In US presidential elections, the more charismatic candidate wins.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
