<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Founders on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1366/tags/founders/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Founders on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1366/tags/founders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Student&#39;s Guide to Startups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/mit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/mit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/mit/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-students-guide-to-startups&#34;&gt;A Student&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Startups&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at MIT.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Till recently graduating seniors had two choices: get a job or go to grad school. I think there will increasingly be a third option: to start your own startup. But how common will that be?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure the default will always be to get a job, but starting a startup could well become as popular as grad school. In the late 90s my professor friends used to complain that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t get grad students, because all the undergrads were going to work for startups. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if that situation returns, but with one difference: this time they&amp;rsquo;ll be starting their own instead of going to work for other people&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Word to the Resourceful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/word/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/word/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/word/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-word-to-the-resourceful&#34;&gt;A Word to the Resourceful&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2012&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year ago I noticed a pattern in the least successful startups we&amp;rsquo;d funded: they all seemed hard to talk to. It felt as if there was some kind of wall between us. I could never quite tell if they understood what I was saying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This caught my attention because earlier we&amp;rsquo;d noticed a pattern among the most successful startups, and it seemed to hinge on a different quality. We found the startups that did best were the ones with the sort of founders about whom we&amp;rsquo;d say &amp;ldquo;they can take care of themselves.&amp;rdquo; The startups that do best are fire-and-forget in the sense that all you have to do is give them a lead, and they&amp;rsquo;ll close it, whatever type of lead it is. When they&amp;rsquo;re raising money, for example, you can do the initial intros knowing that if you wanted to you could stop thinking about it at that point. You won&amp;rsquo;t have to babysit the round to make sure it happens. That type of founder is going to come back with the money; the only question is how much on what terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/ace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/ace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/ace/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;ace&#34;&gt;Ace&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ace December 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I was deciding what to write about next, I was surprised to find that two separate essays I&amp;rsquo;d been planning to write were actually the same.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first is about how to ace your Y Combinator interview. There has been so much nonsense written about this topic that I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning for years to write something telling founders the truth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second is about something politicians sometimes say — that the only way to become a billionaire is by exploiting people — and why this is mistaken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Before the Startup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/before/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/before/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/before/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;before-the-startup&#34;&gt;Before the Startup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a guest lecture in Sam Altman&amp;rsquo;s startup class at Stanford. It&amp;rsquo;s intended for college students, but much of it is applicable to potential founders at other ages.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the advantages of having kids is that when you have to give advice, you can ask yourself &amp;ldquo;what would I tell my own kids?&amp;rdquo; My kids are little, but I can imagine what I&amp;rsquo;d tell them about startups if they were in college, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Control</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/control/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;control&#34;&gt;Control&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;founder-control&#34;&gt;Founder Control&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2010&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Someone we funded is talking to VCs now, and asked me how common it was for a startup&amp;rsquo;s founders to retain control of the board after a series A round. He said VCs told him this almost never happened.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago that was true. In the past, founders rarely kept control of the board through a series A. The traditional series A board consisted of two founders, two VCs, and one independent member. More recently the recipe is often one founder, one VC, and one independent. In either case the founders lose their majority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earnest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/earnest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/earnest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/earnest/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;earnest&#34;&gt;Earnest&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jessica and I have certain words that have special significance when we&amp;rsquo;re talking about startups. The highest compliment we can pay to founders is to describe them as &amp;ldquo;earnest.&amp;rdquo; This is not by itself a guarantee of success. You could be earnest but incapable. But when founders are both formidable (another of our words) and earnest, they&amp;rsquo;re as close to unstoppable as you get.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earnestness sounds like a boring, even Victorian virtue. It seems a bit of an anachronism that people in Silicon Valley would care about it. Why does this matter so much?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Founders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/5founders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/5founders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/5founders/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;five-founders&#34;&gt;Five Founders&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Five Founders April 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inc recently asked me who I thought were the 5 most interesting startup founders of the last 30 years. How do you decide who&amp;rsquo;s the most interesting? The best test seemed to be influence: who are the 5 who&amp;rsquo;ve influenced me most? Who do I use as examples when I&amp;rsquo;m talking to companies we fund? Who do I find myself quoting?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d guess Steve is the most influential founder not just for me but for most people you could ask. A lot of startup culture is Apple culture. He was the original young founder. And while the concept of &amp;ldquo;insanely great&amp;rdquo; already existed in the arts, it was a novel idea to introduce into a company in the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Founder Mode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/foundermode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/foundermode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/foundermode/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;founder-mode&#34;&gt;Founder Mode&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At a YC event last week Brian Chesky gave a talk that everyone who was there will remember. Most founders I talked to afterward said it was the best they&amp;rsquo;d ever heard. Ron Conway, for the first time in his life, forgot to take notes. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to try to reproduce it here. Instead I want to talk about a question it raised.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theme of Brian&amp;rsquo;s talk was that the conventional wisdom about how to run larger companies is mistaken. As Airbnb grew, well-meaning people advised him that he had to run the company in a certain way for it to scale. Their advice could be optimistically summarized as &amp;ldquo;hire good people and give them room to do their jobs.&amp;rdquo; He followed this advice and the results were disastrous. So he had to figure out a better way on his own, which he did partly by studying how Steve Jobs ran Apple. So far it seems to be working. Airbnb&amp;rsquo;s free cash flow margin is now among the best in Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring is Obsolete</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/hiring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/hiring/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;hiring-is-obsolete&#34;&gt;Hiring is Obsolete&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at the Berkeley CSUA.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The three big powers on the Internet now are Yahoo, Google, and Microsoft. Average age of their founders: 24. So it is pretty well established now that grad students can start successful companies. And if grad students can do it, why not undergrads?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like everything else in technology, the cost of starting a startup has decreased dramatically. Now it&amp;rsquo;s so low that it has disappeared into the noise. The main cost of starting a Web-based startup is food and rent. Which means it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost much more to start a company than to be a total slacker. You can probably start a startup on ten thousand dollars of seed funding, if you&amp;rsquo;re prepared to live on ramen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jessica Livingston</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/jessica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/jessica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/jessica/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;jessica-livingston&#34;&gt;Jessica Livingston&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2015&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few months ago an article about Y Combinator said that early on it had been a &amp;ldquo;one-man show.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s sadly common to read that sort of thing. But the problem with that description is not just that it&amp;rsquo;s unfair. It&amp;rsquo;s also misleading. Much of what&amp;rsquo;s most novel about YC is due to Jessica Livingston. If you don&amp;rsquo;t understand her, you don&amp;rsquo;t understand YC. So let me tell you a little about Jessica.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning from Founders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/foundersatwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/foundersatwork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/foundersatwork/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-from-founders&#34;&gt;Learning from Founders&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Foreword to Jessica Livingston&amp;rsquo;s Founders at Work.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apparently sprinters reach their highest speed right out of the blocks, and spend the rest of the race slowing down. The winners slow down the least. It&amp;rsquo;s that way with most startups too. The earliest phase is usually the most productive. That&amp;rsquo;s when they have the really big ideas. Imagine what Apple was like when 100% of its employees were either Steve Jobs or Steve Wozniak.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not Not</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/notnot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/notnot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/notnot/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;not-not&#34;&gt;Not Not&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from talks at the 2007 Startup School and the Berkeley CSUA.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve now been doing Y Combinator long enough to have some data about success rates. Our first batch, in the summer of 2005, had eight startups in it. Of those eight, it now looks as if at least four succeeded. Three have been acquired: Reddit was a merger of two, Reddit and Infogami, and a third was acquired that we can&amp;rsquo;t talk about yet. Another from that batch was Loopt, which is doing so well they could probably be acquired in about ten minutes if they wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relentlessly Resourceful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/relres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/relres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/relres/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;relentlessly-resourceful&#34;&gt;Relentlessly Resourceful&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago I finally got being a good startup founder down to two words: relentlessly resourceful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Till then the best I&amp;rsquo;d managed was to get the opposite quality down to one: hapless. Most dictionaries say hapless means unlucky. But the dictionaries are not doing a very good job. A team that outplays its opponents but loses because of a bad decision by the referee could be called unlucky, but not hapless. Hapless implies passivity. To be hapless is to be battered by circumstances — to let the world have its way with you, instead of having your way with the world. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startups in 13 Sentences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/13sentences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/13sentences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/13sentences/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;startups-in-13-sentences&#34;&gt;Startups in 13 Sentences&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator. Watch how this essay was written. February 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the things I always tell startups is a principle I learned from Paul Buchheit: it&amp;rsquo;s better to make a few people really happy than to make a lot of people semi-happy. I was saying recently to a reporter that if I could only tell startups 10 things, this would be one of them. Then I thought: what would the other 9 be?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Airbnbs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/airbnbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/airbnbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/airbnbs/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-airbnbs&#34;&gt;The Airbnbs&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To celebrate Airbnb&amp;rsquo;s IPO and to help future founders, I thought it might be useful to explain what was special about Airbnb.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What was special about the Airbnbs was how earnest they were. They did nothing half-way, and we could sense this even in the interview. Sometimes after we interviewed a startup we&amp;rsquo;d be uncertain what to do, and have to talk it over. Other times we&amp;rsquo;d just look at one another and smile. The Airbnbs&amp;rsquo; interview was that kind. We didn&amp;rsquo;t even like the idea that much. Nor did users, at that stage; they had no growth. But the founders seemed so full of energy that it was impossible not to like them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Founder Visa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/foundervisa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/foundervisa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/foundervisa/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-founder-visa&#34;&gt;The Founder Visa&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I usually avoid politics, but since we now seem to have an administration that&amp;rsquo;s open to suggestions, I&amp;rsquo;m going to risk making one. The single biggest thing the government could do to increase the number of startups in this country is a policy that would cost nothing: establish a new class of visa for startup founders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest constraint on the number of new startups that get created in the US is not tax policy or employment law or even Sarbanes-Oxley. It&amp;rsquo;s that we won&amp;rsquo;t let the people who want to start them into the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Startup Funding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/future/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-future-of-startup-funding&#34;&gt;The Future of Startup Funding&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2010&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago I wrote about what I called &amp;ldquo;a huge, unexploited opportunity in startup funding:&amp;rdquo; the growing disconnect between VCs, whose current business model requires them to invest large amounts, and a large class of startups that need less than they used to. Increasingly, startups want a couple hundred thousand dollars, not a couple million. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Kate Saw in Silicon Valley</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/kate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/kate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/kate/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-kate-saw-in-silicon-valley&#34;&gt;What Kate Saw in Silicon Valley&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kate Courteau is the architect who designed Y Combinator&amp;rsquo;s office. Recently we managed to recruit her to help us run YC when she&amp;rsquo;s not busy with architectural projects. Though she&amp;rsquo;d heard a lot about YC since the beginning, the last 9 months have been a total immersion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been around the startup world for so long that it seems normal to me, so I was curious to hear what had surprised her most about it. This was her list:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What We Look for in Founders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/founders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/founders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/founders/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-we-look-for-in-founders&#34;&gt;What We Look for in Founders&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2010&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(I wrote this for Forbes, who asked me to write something about the qualities we look for in founders. In print they had to cut the last item because they didn&amp;rsquo;t have room.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-determination&#34;&gt;1. Determination&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This has turned out to be the most important quality in startup founders. We thought when we started Y Combinator that the most important quality would be intelligence. That&amp;rsquo;s the myth in the Valley. And certainly you don&amp;rsquo;t want founders to be stupid. But as long as you&amp;rsquo;re over a certain threshold of intelligence, what matters most is determination. You&amp;rsquo;re going to hit a lot of obstacles. You can&amp;rsquo;t be the sort of person who gets demoralized easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why It&#39;s Safe for Founders to Be Nice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/safe/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-its-safe-for-founders-to-be-nice&#34;&gt;Why It&amp;rsquo;s Safe for Founders to Be Nice&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2015&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently got an email from a founder that helped me understand something important: why it&amp;rsquo;s safe for startup founders to be nice people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I grew up with a cartoon idea of a very successful businessman (in the cartoon it was always a man): a rapacious, cigar-smoking, table-thumping guy in his fifties who wins by exercising power, and isn&amp;rsquo;t too fussy about how. As I&amp;rsquo;ve written before, one of the things that has surprised me most about startups is how few of the most successful founders are like that. Maybe successful people in other industries are; I don&amp;rsquo;t know; but not startup founders. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why to Start a Startup in a Bad Economy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/badeconomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_en/badeconomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1366/paul_graham/essays_zh/badeconomy/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-to-start-a-startup-in-a-bad-economy&#34;&gt;Why to Start a Startup in a Bad Economy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The economic situation is apparently so grim that some experts fear we may be in for a stretch as bad as the mid seventies. When Microsoft and Apple were founded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As those examples suggest, a recession may not be such a bad time to start a startup. I&amp;rsquo;m not claiming it&amp;rsquo;s a particularly good time either. The truth is more boring: the state of the economy doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter much either way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
