<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entrepreneurship on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1326/tags/entrepreneurship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entrepreneurship on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1326/tags/entrepreneurship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A New Venture Animal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/ycombinator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/ycombinator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/ycombinator/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-new-venture-animal&#34;&gt;A New Venture Animal&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2008, rev May 2013&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay grew out of something I wrote for myself to figure out what we do. Even though Y Combinator is now 3 years old, we&amp;rsquo;re still trying to understand its implications.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was annoyed recently to read a description of Y Combinator that said &amp;ldquo;Y Combinator does seed funding for startups.&amp;rdquo; What was especially annoying about it was that I wrote it. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t really convey what we do. And the reason it&amp;rsquo;s inaccurate is that, paradoxically, funding very early stage startups is not mainly about funding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Student&#39;s Guide to Startups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/mit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/mit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/mit/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-students-guide-to-startups&#34;&gt;A Student&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Startups&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at MIT.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Till recently graduating seniors had two choices: get a job or go to grad school. I think there will increasingly be a third option: to start your own startup. But how common will that be?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure the default will always be to get a job, but starting a startup could well become as popular as grad school. In the late 90s my professor friends used to complain that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t get grad students, because all the undergrads were going to work for startups. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if that situation returns, but with one difference: this time they&amp;rsquo;ll be starting their own instead of going to work for other people&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Before the Startup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/before/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/before/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/before/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;before-the-startup&#34;&gt;Before the Startup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a guest lecture in Sam Altman&amp;rsquo;s startup class at Stanford. It&amp;rsquo;s intended for college students, but much of it is applicable to potential founders at other ages.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the advantages of having kids is that when you have to give advice, you can ask yourself &amp;ldquo;what would I tell my own kids?&amp;rdquo; My kids are little, but I can imagine what I&amp;rsquo;d tell them about startups if they were in college, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Could VC be a Casualty of the Recession?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/divergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/divergence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/divergence/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;could-vc-be-a-casualty-of-the-recession&#34;&gt;Could VC be a Casualty of the Recession?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(I originally wrote this at the request of a company producing a report about entrepreneurship. Unfortunately after reading it they decided it was too controversial to include.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VC funding will probably dry up somewhat during the present recession, like it usually does in bad times. But this time the result may be different. This time the number of new startups may not decrease. And that could be dangerous for VCs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Things that Don&#39;t Scale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/ds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/ds/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;do-things-that-dont-scale&#34;&gt;Do Things that Don&amp;rsquo;t Scale&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-things-that-dont-scale-1&#34;&gt;Do Things that Don&amp;rsquo;t Scale&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2013&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most common types of advice we give at Y Combinator is to do things that don&amp;rsquo;t scale. A lot of would-be founders believe that startups either take off or don&amp;rsquo;t. You build something, make it available, and if you&amp;rsquo;ve made a better mousetrap, people beat a path to your door as promised. Or they don&amp;rsquo;t, in which case the market must not exist. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Not to Die</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/die/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/die/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/die/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-not-to-die&#34;&gt;How Not to Die&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This is a talk I gave at the last Y Combinator dinner of the summer. Usually we don&amp;rsquo;t have a speaker at the last dinner; it&amp;rsquo;s more of a party. But it seemed worth spoiling the atmosphere if I could save some of the startups from preventable deaths. So at the last minute I cooked up this rather grim talk. I didn&amp;rsquo;t mean this as an essay; I wrote it down because I only had two hours before dinner and think fastest while writing.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How People Get Rich Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/richnow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/richnow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/richnow/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-people-get-rich-now&#34;&gt;How People Get Rich Now&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every year since 1982, Forbes magazine has published a list of the richest Americans. If we compare the 100 richest people in 1982 to the 100 richest in 2020, we notice some big differences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1982 the most common source of wealth was inheritance. Of the 100 richest people, 60 inherited from an ancestor. There were 10 du Pont heirs alone. By 2020 the number of heirs had been cut in half, accounting for only 27 of the biggest 100 fortunes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Fund a Startup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/startupfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/startupfunding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/startupfunding/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-fund-a-startup&#34;&gt;How to Fund a Startup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Venture funding works like gears. A typical startup goes through several rounds of funding, and at each round you want to take just enough money to reach the speed where you can shift into the next gear.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few startups get it quite right. Many are underfunded. A few are overfunded, which is like trying to start driving in third gear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Get Startup Ideas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/startupideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/startupideas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/startupideas/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-get-startup-ideas&#34;&gt;How to Get Startup Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2012&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The way to get startup ideas is not to try to think of startup ideas. It&amp;rsquo;s to look for problems, preferably problems you have yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The very best startup ideas tend to have three things in common: they&amp;rsquo;re something the founders themselves want, that they themselves can build, and that few others realize are worth doing. Microsoft, Apple, Yahoo, Google, and Facebook all began this way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Pittsburgh a Startup Hub</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/pgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/pgh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/pgh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-make-pittsburgh-a-startup-hub&#34;&gt;How to Make Pittsburgh a Startup Hub&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2016&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This is a talk I gave at an event called Opt412 in Pittsburgh. Much of it will apply to other towns. But not all, because as I say in the talk, Pittsburgh has some important advantages over most would-be startup hubs.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What would it take to make Pittsburgh into a startup hub, like Silicon Valley? I understand Pittsburgh pretty well, because I grew up here, in Monroeville. And I understand Silicon Valley pretty well because that&amp;rsquo;s where I live now. Could you get that kind of startup ecosystem going here?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Start a Startup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/start/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-start-a-startup&#34;&gt;How to Start a Startup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at the Harvard Computer Society.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You need three things to create a successful startup: to start with good people, to make something customers actually want, and to spend as little money as possible. Most startups that fail do it because they fail at one of these. A startup that does all three will probably succeed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ideas for Startups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/ideas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/ideas/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;ideas-for-startups&#34;&gt;Ideas for Startups&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at the 2005 Startup School.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do you get good ideas for startups? That&amp;rsquo;s probably the number one question people ask me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to reply with another question: why do people think it&amp;rsquo;s hard to come up with ideas for startups?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That might seem a stupid thing to ask. Why do they think it&amp;rsquo;s hard? If people can&amp;rsquo;t do it, then it is hard, at least for them. Right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maybe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/maybe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/maybe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/maybe/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;maybe&#34;&gt;Maybe&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;February 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of cities look at Silicon Valley and ask &amp;ldquo;How could we make something like that happen here?&amp;rdquo; The organic way to do it is to establish a first-rate university in a place where rich people want to live. That&amp;rsquo;s how Silicon Valley happened. But could you shortcut the process by funding startups?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Possibly. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider what it would take.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first thing to understand is that encouraging startups is a different problem from encouraging startups in a particular city. The latter is much more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mean</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/mean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/mean/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;mean&#34;&gt;Mean&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It struck me recently how few of the most successful people I know are mean. There are exceptions, but remarkably few.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanness isn&amp;rsquo;t rare. In fact, one of the things the internet has shown us is how mean people can be. A few decades ago, only famous people and professional writers got to publish their opinions. Now everyone can, and we can all see the long tail of meanness that had previously been hidden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not Not</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/notnot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/notnot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/notnot/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;not-not&#34;&gt;Not Not&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from talks at the 2007 Startup School and the Berkeley CSUA.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve now been doing Y Combinator long enough to have some data about success rates. Our first batch, in the summer of 2005, had eight startups in it. Of those eight, it now looks as if at least four succeeded. Three have been acquired: Reddit was a merger of two, Reddit and Infogami, and a third was acquired that we can&amp;rsquo;t talk about yet. Another from that batch was Loopt, which is doing so well they could probably be acquired in about ten minutes if they wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic Startup Ideas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/organic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/organic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;organic-startup-ideas&#34;&gt;Organic Startup Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2010&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best way to come up with startup ideas is to ask yourself the question: what do you wish someone would make for you?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two types of startup ideas: those that grow organically out of your own life, and those that you decide, from afar, are going to be necessary to some class of users other than you. Apple was the first type. Apple happened because Steve Wozniak wanted a computer. Unlike most people who wanted computers, he could design one, so he did. And since lots of other people wanted the same thing, Apple was able to sell enough of them to get the company rolling. They still rely on this principle today, incidentally. The iPhone is the phone Steve Jobs wants. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relentlessly Resourceful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/relres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/relres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/relres/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;relentlessly-resourceful&#34;&gt;Relentlessly Resourceful&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago I finally got being a good startup founder down to two words: relentlessly resourceful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Till then the best I&amp;rsquo;d managed was to get the opposite quality down to one: hapless. Most dictionaries say hapless means unlucky. But the dictionaries are not doing a very good job. A team that outplays its opponents but loses because of a bad decision by the referee could be called unlucky, but not hapless. Hapless implies passivity. To be hapless is to be battered by circumstances — to let the world have its way with you, instead of having your way with the world. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schlep Blindness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/schlep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/schlep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/schlep/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;schlep-blindness&#34;&gt;Schlep Blindness&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2012&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are great startup ideas lying around unexploited right under our noses. One reason we don&amp;rsquo;t see them is a phenomenon I call schlep blindness. Schlep was originally a Yiddish word but has passed into general use in the US. It means a tedious, unpleasant task.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No one likes schleps, but hackers especially dislike them. Most hackers who start startups wish they could do it by just writing some clever software, putting it on a server somewhere, and watching the money roll in—without ever having to talk to users, or negotiate with other companies, or deal with other people&amp;rsquo;s broken code. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s possible, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 18 Mistakes That Kill Startups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/startupmistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/startupmistakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/startupmistakes/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-18-mistakes-that-kill-startups&#34;&gt;The 18 Mistakes That Kill Startups&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Q &amp;amp; A period after a recent talk, someone asked what made startups fail. After standing there gaping for a few seconds I realized this was kind of a trick question. It&amp;rsquo;s equivalent to asking how to make a startup succeed — if you avoid every cause of failure, you succeed — and that&amp;rsquo;s too big a question to answer on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Airbnbs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/airbnbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/airbnbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/airbnbs/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-airbnbs&#34;&gt;The Airbnbs&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To celebrate Airbnb&amp;rsquo;s IPO and to help future founders, I thought it might be useful to explain what was special about Airbnb.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What was special about the Airbnbs was how earnest they were. They did nothing half-way, and we could sense this even in the interview. Sometimes after we interviewed a startup we&amp;rsquo;d be uncertain what to do, and have to talk it over. Other times we&amp;rsquo;d just look at one another and smile. The Airbnbs&amp;rsquo; interview was that kind. We didn&amp;rsquo;t even like the idea that much. Nor did users, at that stage; they had no growth. But the founders seemed so full of energy that it was impossible not to like them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fatal Pinch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/pinch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/pinch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/pinch/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-fatal-pinch&#34;&gt;The Fatal Pinch&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many startups go through a point a few months before they die where although they have a significant amount of money in the bank, they&amp;rsquo;re also losing a lot each month, and revenue growth is either nonexistent or mediocre. The company has, say, 6 months of runway. Or to put it more brutally, 6 months before they&amp;rsquo;re out of business. They expect to avoid that by raising more from investors. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hardest Lessons for Startups to Learn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/startuplessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/startuplessons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/startuplessons/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-hardest-lessons-for-startups-to-learn&#34;&gt;The Hardest Lessons for Startups to Learn&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at the 2006 Startup School.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The startups we&amp;rsquo;ve funded so far are pretty quick, but they seem quicker to learn some lessons than others. I think it&amp;rsquo;s because some things about startups are kind of counterintuitive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve now invested in enough companies that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a trick for determining which points are the counterintuitive ones: they&amp;rsquo;re the ones I have to keep repeating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pooled-Risk Company Management Company</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/prcmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/prcmc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/prcmc/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-pooled-risk-company-management-company&#34;&gt;The Pooled-Risk Company Management Company&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At this year&amp;rsquo;s startup school, David Heinemeier Hansson gave a talk in which he suggested that startup founders should do things the old fashioned way. Instead of hoping to get rich by building a valuable company and then selling stock in a &amp;ldquo;liquidity event,&amp;rdquo; founders should start companies that make money and live off the revenues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sounds like a good plan. Let&amp;rsquo;s think about the optimal way to do this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Did this Summer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/sfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/sfp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/sfp/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-i-did-this-summer&#34;&gt;What I Did this Summer&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first Summer Founders Program has just finished. We were surprised how well it went. Overall only about 10% of startups succeed, but if I had to guess now, I&amp;rsquo;d predict three or four of the eight startups we funded will make it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of the startups that needed further funding, I believe all have either closed a round or are likely to soon. Two have already turned down (lowball) acquisition offers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve Learned from Users</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/users/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-ive-learned-from-users&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve Learned from Users&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently told applicants to Y Combinator that the best advice I could give for getting in, per word, was &amp;ldquo;Explain what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned from users.&amp;rdquo; That tests a lot of things: whether you&amp;rsquo;re paying attention to users, how well you understand them, and even how much they need what you&amp;rsquo;re making.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Afterward I asked myself the same question. What have I learned from YC&amp;rsquo;s users, the startups we&amp;rsquo;ve funded?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Startup Hubs Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/hubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/hubs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/hubs/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-startup-hubs-work&#34;&gt;Why Startup Hubs Work&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2011&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you look at a list of US cities sorted by population, the number of successful startups per capita varies by orders of magnitude. Somehow it&amp;rsquo;s as if most places were sprayed with startupicide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wondered about this for years. I could see the average town was like a roach motel for startup ambitions: smart, ambitious people went in, but no startups came out. But I was never able to figure out exactly what happened inside the motel—exactly what was killing all the potential startups. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Startups Condense in America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/america/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/america/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-startups-condense-in-america&#34;&gt;Why Startups Condense in America&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a keynote at Xtech.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Startups happen in clusters. There are a lot of them in Silicon Valley and Boston, and few in Chicago or Miami. A country that wants startups will probably also have to reproduce whatever makes these clusters form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve claimed that the recipe is a great university near a town smart people like. If you set up those conditions within the US, startups will form as inevitably as water droplets condense on a cold piece of metal. But when I consider what it would take to reproduce Silicon Valley in another country, it&amp;rsquo;s clear the US is a particularly humid environment. Startups condense more easily here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why to Move to a Startup Hub</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/startuphubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/startuphubs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/startuphubs/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-to-move-to-a-startup-hub&#34;&gt;Why to Move to a Startup Hub&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the last talk I gave, one of the organizers got up on the stage to deliver an impromptu rebuttal. That never happened before. I only heard the first few sentences, but that was enough to tell what I said that upset him: that startups would do better if they moved to Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This conference was in London, and most of the audience seemed to be from the UK. So saying startups should move to Silicon Valley seemed like a nationalistic remark: an obnoxious American telling them that if they wanted to do things right they should all just move to America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why YC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/whyyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/whyyc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/whyyc/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-yc&#34;&gt;Why YC&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2006, rev August 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday one of the founders we funded asked me why we started Y Combinator. Or more precisely, he asked if we&amp;rsquo;d started YC mainly for fun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kind of, but not quite. It is enormously fun to be able to work with Rtm and Trevor again. I missed that after we sold Viaweb, and for all the years after I always had a background process running, looking for something we could do together. There is definitely an aspect of a band reunion to Y Combinator. Every couple days I slip and call it &amp;ldquo;Viaweb.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
