<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Time Management on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/time-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Time Management on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:11:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/time-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What are some useful, but little-known, features of the tools used in professional mathematics?</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/what-are-some-useful-but-little-known-features-of-the-tools-used-in-professional-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/what-are-some-useful-but-little-known-features-of-the-tools-used-in-professional-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/zh/what-are-some-useful-but-little-known-features-of-the-tools-used-in-professional-mathematics.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/2017/07/07/what-are-some-useful-but-little-known-features-of-the-tools-used-in-professional-mathematics/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-are-some-useful-but-little-known-features-of-the-tools-used-in-professional-mathematics&#34;&gt;What are some useful, but little-known, features of the tools used in professional mathematics?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I was talking with Ed Dunne, who is currently the Executive Editor of Mathematical Reviews (and in particular with its online incarnation at MathSciNet). At the time, I was mentioning how laborious it was for me to create a BibTeX file for dozens of references by using MathSciNet to locate each reference separately, and to export each one to BibTeX format. He then informed me that underneath to every MathSciNet reference there was a little link to add the reference to a Clipboard, and then one could export the entire Clipboard at once to whatever format one wished. In retrospect, this was a functionality of the site that had always been visible, but I had never bothered to explore it, and now I can populate a BibTeX file much more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks are not the same as papers</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/talks-are-not-the-same-as-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/talks-are-not-the-same-as-papers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/zh/talks-are-not-the-same-as-papers.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/talks-are-not-the-same-as-papers/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;talks-are-not-the-same-as-papers&#34;&gt;Talks are not the same as papers&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The mediocre teacher tells. The good teacher explains. The superior teacher demonstrates. The great teacher inspires.&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Arthur_Ward&#34;&gt;William Ward&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to give good talks, especially when one is just starting out one’s career.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One should avoid the common error of treating a talk like a paper, with all the attendant details, technicalities, and formalism. (In particular, one should &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; give a talk which consists solely of transparencies of one’s research paper!) Such talks are almost impossible for anyone not intimately familiar with your work to be able to follow, especially since (unlike when reading a paper) it is difficult for an audience member to refer back to notation that had been defined, or comments that had been made, four slides or five blackboards ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be professional in your work</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/be-professional-in-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 19:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/be-professional-in-your-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/zh/be-professional-in-your-work.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/be-professional-in-your-work/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;be-professional-in-your-work&#34;&gt;Be professional in your work&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Integrity without knowledge is weak and useless, and knowledge without integrity is dangerous and dreadful.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;(Samuel Johnson, &amp;ldquo;Rasselas&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Take your duties and responsibilities seriously; being frivolous is fine with friends, but can be annoying for your colleagues, especially those who are busy with similar responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exercise professional courtesy and respect for the time and efforts of your colleagues. Unless you are already on good casual terms with the person you are interacting with, send them an email (or text, if you are close enough to share phone numbers) to schedule a call or meeting rather than just showing up or calling unannounced. If you have an appointment, be on time; being too late or too early can disrupt your colleague&amp;rsquo;s other plans for the day and can also be viewed as a sign of disrespect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work hard</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/work-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/work-hard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/zh/work-hard.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/work-hard/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;work-hard&#34;&gt;Work hard&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every mathematician worthy of the name has experienced … the state of lucid exaltation in which one thought succeeds another as if miraculously… this feeling may last for hours at a time, even for days. Once you have experienced it, you are eager to repeat it but unable to do it at will, unless perhaps by dogged work…&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andr%C3%A9_Weil&#34;&gt;André Weil&lt;/a&gt;, “The Apprenticeship of a Mathematician”)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relying on intelligence alone to pull things off at the last minute may work for a while, but, generally speaking, at the graduate level or higher it doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
