<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Independent Thinking on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1326/tags/independent-thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Independent Thinking on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1326/tags/independent-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Think for Yourself</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/think/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/think/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/think/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-think-for-yourself&#34;&gt;How to Think for Yourself&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some kinds of work that you can&amp;rsquo;t do well without thinking differently from your peers. To be a successful scientist, for example, it&amp;rsquo;s not enough just to be correct. Your ideas have to be both correct and novel. You can&amp;rsquo;t publish papers saying things other people already know. You need to say things no one else has realized yet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The same is true for investors. It&amp;rsquo;s not enough for a public market investor to predict correctly how a company will do. If a lot of other people make the same prediction, the stock price will already reflect it, and there&amp;rsquo;s no room to make money. The only valuable insights are the ones most other investors don&amp;rsquo;t share.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mod</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/mod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/mod/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mod&#34;&gt;Mod&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-two-kinds-of-moderate&#34;&gt;The Two Kinds of Moderate&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2019&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two distinct ways to be politically moderate: on purpose and by accident. Intentional moderates are trimmers, deliberately choosing a position mid-way between the extremes of right and left. Accidental moderates end up in the middle, on average, because they make up their own minds about each question, and the far right and far left are roughly equally wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can distinguish intentional from accidental moderates by the distribution of their opinions. If the far left opinion on some matter is 0 and the far right opinion 100, an intentional moderate&amp;rsquo;s opinion on every question will be near 50. Whereas an accidental moderate&amp;rsquo;s opinions will be scattered over a broad range, but will, like those of the intentional moderate, average to about 50.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orthodox Privilege</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/orth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/orth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;orthodox-privilege&#34;&gt;Orthodox Privilege&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Few people are capable of expressing with equanimity opinions which differ from the prejudices of their social environment. Most people are even incapable of forming such opinions.&amp;quot;— Einstein&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of talk about privilege lately. Although the concept is overused, there is something to it, and in particular to the idea that privilege makes you blind — that you can&amp;rsquo;t see things that are visible to someone whose life is very different from yours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
