<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Product Development on Linguage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1326/tags/product-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Product Development on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1326/tags/product-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hiring is Obsolete</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/hiring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_zh/hiring/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;hiring-is-obsolete&#34;&gt;Hiring is Obsolete&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at the Berkeley CSUA.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The three big powers on the Internet now are Yahoo, Google, and Microsoft. Average age of their founders: 24. So it is pretty well established now that grad students can start successful companies. And if grad students can do it, why not undergrads?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like everything else in technology, the cost of starting a startup has decreased dramatically. Now it&amp;rsquo;s so low that it has disappeared into the noise. The main cost of starting a Web-based startup is food and rent. Which means it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost much more to start a company than to be a total slacker. You can probably start a startup on ten thousand dollars of seed funding, if you&amp;rsquo;re prepared to live on ramen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic Startup Ideas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/organic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1326/paul_graham/essays_en/organic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;organic-startup-ideas&#34;&gt;Organic Startup Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2010&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to start a startup? Get funded by Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best way to come up with startup ideas is to ask yourself the question: what do you wish someone would make for you?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two types of startup ideas: those that grow organically out of your own life, and those that you decide, from afar, are going to be necessary to some class of users other than you. Apple was the first type. Apple happened because Steve Wozniak wanted a computer. Unlike most people who wanted computers, he could design one, so he did. And since lots of other people wanted the same thing, Apple was able to sell enough of them to get the company rolling. They still rely on this principle today, incidentally. The iPhone is the phone Steve Jobs wants. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
