<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Media on Linguista</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1355/tags/media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Media on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1355/tags/media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus and Credibility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/cred/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/cred/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/cred/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;coronavirus-and-credibility&#34;&gt;Coronavirus and Credibility&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a video of TV journalists and politicians confidently saying that the coronavirus would be no worse than the flu. What struck me about it was not just how mistaken they seemed, but how daring. How could they feel safe saying such things?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The answer, I realized, is that they didn&amp;rsquo;t think they could get caught. They didn&amp;rsquo;t realize there was any danger in making false predictions. These people constantly make false predictions, and get away with it, because the things they make predictions about either have mushy enough outcomes that they can bluster their way out of trouble, or happen so far in the future that few remember what they said.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-Medium Publishing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/publishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;post-medium-publishing&#34;&gt;Post-Medium Publishing&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Publishers of all types, from news to music, are unhappy that consumers won&amp;rsquo;t pay for content anymore. At least, that&amp;rsquo;s how they see it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In fact consumers never really were paying for content, and publishers weren&amp;rsquo;t really selling it either. If the content was what they were selling, why has the price of books or music or movies always depended mostly on the format? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t better content cost more? [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The List of N Things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/nthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/nthings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/nthings/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-list-of-n-things&#34;&gt;The List of N Things&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bet you the current issue of Cosmopolitan has an article whose title begins with a number. &amp;ldquo;7 Things He Won&amp;rsquo;t Tell You about Sex,&amp;rdquo; or something like that. Some popular magazines feature articles of this type on the cover of every issue. That can&amp;rsquo;t be happening by accident. Editors must know they attract readers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why do readers like the list of n things so much? Mainly because it&amp;rsquo;s easier to read than a regular article. [1] Structurally, the list of n things is a degenerate case of essay. An essay can go anywhere the writer wants. In a list of n things the writer agrees to constrain himself to a collection of points of roughly equal importance, and he tells the reader explicitly what they are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Submarine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/submarine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/submarine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/submarine/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-submarine&#34;&gt;The Submarine&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Suits make a corporate comeback,&amp;rdquo; says the New York Times. Why does this sound familiar? Maybe because the suit was also back in February, September 2004, June 2004, March 2004, September 2003, November 2002, April 2002, and February 2002. Why do the media keep running stories saying suits are back? Because PR firms tell them to. One of the most surprising things I discovered during my brief business career was the existence of the PR industry, lurking like a huge, quiet submarine beneath the news. Of the stories you read in traditional media that aren&amp;rsquo;t about politics, crimes, or disasters, more than half probably come from PR firms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why TV Lost</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/convergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/convergence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/convergence/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-tv-lost&#34;&gt;Why TV Lost&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About twenty years ago people noticed computers and TV were on a collision course and started to speculate about what they&amp;rsquo;d produce when they converged. We now know the answer: computers. It&amp;rsquo;s clear now that even by using the word &amp;ldquo;convergence&amp;rdquo; we were giving TV too much credit. This won&amp;rsquo;t be convergence so much as replacement. People may still watch things they call &amp;ldquo;TV shows,&amp;rdquo; but they&amp;rsquo;ll watch them mostly on computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
