<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Success on Linguage</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/success/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Success on Linguage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cities and Ambition</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/cities/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;cities-and-ambition&#34;&gt;Cities and Ambition&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2008&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great cities attract ambitious people. You can sense it when you walk around one. In a hundred subtle ways, the city sends you a message: you could do more; you should try harder.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The surprising thing is how different these messages can be. New York tells you, above all: you should make more money. There are other messages too, of course. You should be hipper. You should be better looking. But the clearest message is that you should be richer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earnest</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/earnest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/earnest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/earnest/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;earnest&#34;&gt;Earnest&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jessica and I have certain words that have special significance when we&amp;rsquo;re talking about startups. The highest compliment we can pay to founders is to describe them as &amp;ldquo;earnest.&amp;rdquo; This is not by itself a guarantee of success. You could be earnest but incapable. But when founders are both formidable (another of our words) and earnest, they&amp;rsquo;re as close to unstoppable as you get.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earnestness sounds like a boring, even Victorian virtue. It seems a bit of an anachronism that people in Silicon Valley would care about it. Why does this matter so much?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fierce Nerds</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/fn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/fn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/fn/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;fierce-nerds&#34;&gt;Fierce Nerds&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most people think of nerds as quiet, diffident people. In ordinary social situations they are — as quiet and diffident as the star quarterback would be if he found himself in the middle of a physics symposium. And for the same reason: they are fish out of water. But the apparent diffidence of nerds is an illusion due to the fact that when non-nerds observe them, it&amp;rsquo;s usually in ordinary social situations. In fact some nerds are quite fierce.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haters</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/fh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/fh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/fh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;haters&#34;&gt;Haters&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(I originally intended this for startup founders, who are often surprised by the attention they get as their companies grow, but it applies equally to anyone who becomes famous.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you become sufficiently famous, you&amp;rsquo;ll acquire some fans who like you too much. These people are sometimes called &amp;ldquo;fanboys,&amp;rdquo; and though I dislike that term, I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to use it here. We need some word for them, because this is a distinct phenomenon from someone simply liking your work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Not to Die</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/die/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/die/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/die/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-not-to-die&#34;&gt;How Not to Die&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This is a talk I gave at the last Y Combinator dinner of the summer. Usually we don&amp;rsquo;t have a speaker at the last dinner; it&amp;rsquo;s more of a party. But it seemed worth spoiling the atmosphere if I could save some of the startups from preventable deaths. So at the last minute I cooked up this rather grim talk. I didn&amp;rsquo;t mean this as an essay; I wrote it down because I only had two hours before dinner and think fastest while writing.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Do What You Love</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/love/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-do-what-you-love&#34;&gt;How to Do What You Love&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To do something well you have to like it. That idea is not exactly novel. We&amp;rsquo;ve got it down to four words: &amp;ldquo;Do what you love.&amp;rdquo; But it&amp;rsquo;s not enough just to tell people that. Doing what you love is complicated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The very idea is foreign to what most of us learn as kids. When I was a kid, it seemed as if work and fun were opposites by definition. Life had two states: some of the time adults were making you do things, and that was called work; the rest of the time you could do what you wanted, and that was called playing. Occasionally the things adults made you do were fun, just as, occasionally, playing wasn&amp;rsquo;t — for example, if you fell and hurt yourself. But except for these few anomalous cases, work was pretty much defined as not-fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Work Hard</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/hwh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/hwh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/hwh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-work-hard&#34;&gt;How to Work Hard&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;June 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It might not seem there&amp;rsquo;s much to learn about how to work hard. Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s been to school knows what it entails, even if they chose not to do it. There are 12 year olds who work amazingly hard. And yet when I ask if I know more about working hard now than when I was in school, the answer is definitely yes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mean</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/mean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/mean/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;mean&#34;&gt;Mean&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It struck me recently how few of the most successful people I know are mean. There are exceptions, but remarkably few.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanness isn&amp;rsquo;t rare. In fact, one of the things the internet has shown us is how mean people can be. A few decades ago, only famous people and professional writers got to publish their opinions. Now everyone can, and we can all see the long tail of meanness that had previously been hidden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News from the Front</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/colleges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/colleges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/colleges/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;news-from-the-front&#34;&gt;News from the Front&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I had a thought so heretical that it really surprised me. It may not matter all that much where you go to college.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For me, as for a lot of middle class kids, getting into a good college was more or less the meaning of life when I was growing up. What was I? A student. To do that well meant to get good grades. Why did one have to get good grades? To get into a good college. And why did one want to do that? There seemed to be several reasons: you&amp;rsquo;d learn more, get better jobs, make more money. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t matter exactly what the benefits would be. College was a bottleneck through which all your future prospects passed; everything would be better if you went to a better college.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relentlessly Resourceful</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/relres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/relres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/relres/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;relentlessly-resourceful&#34;&gt;Relentlessly Resourceful&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago I finally got being a good startup founder down to two words: relentlessly resourceful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Till then the best I&amp;rsquo;d managed was to get the opposite quality down to one: hapless. Most dictionaries say hapless means unlucky. But the dictionaries are not doing a very good job. A team that outplays its opponents but loses because of a bad decision by the referee could be called unlucky, but not hapless. Hapless implies passivity. To be hapless is to be battered by circumstances — to let the world have its way with you, instead of having your way with the world. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superlinear Returns</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/superlinear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/superlinear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/superlinear/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;superlinear-returns&#34;&gt;Superlinear Returns&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand about the world when I was a child is the degree to which the returns for performance are superlinear.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Teachers and coaches implicitly told us the returns were linear. &amp;ldquo;You get out,&amp;rdquo; I heard a thousand times, &amp;ldquo;what you put in.&amp;rdquo; They meant well, but this is rarely true. If your product is only half as good as your competitor&amp;rsquo;s, you don&amp;rsquo;t get half as many customers. You get no customers, and you go out of business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Anatomy of Determination</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/determination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/determination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/determination/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-anatomy-of-determination&#34;&gt;The Anatomy of Determination&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2009&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like all investors, we spend a lot of time trying to learn how to predict which startups will succeed. We probably spend more time thinking about it than most, because we invest the earliest. Prediction is usually all we have to rely on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We learned quickly that the most important predictor of success is determination. At first we thought it might be intelligence. Everyone likes to believe that&amp;rsquo;s what makes startups succeed. It makes a better story that a company won because its founders were so smart. The PR people and reporters who spread such stories probably believe them themselves. But while it certainly helps to be smart, it&amp;rsquo;s not the deciding factor. There are plenty of people as smart as Bill Gates who achieve nothing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of the Marginal</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/marginal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/marginal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-power-of-the-marginal&#34;&gt;The Power of the Marginal&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;June 2006&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from talks at Usenix 2006 and Railsconf 2006.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago my friend Trevor and I went to look at the Apple garage. As we stood there, he said that as a kid growing up in Saskatchewan he&amp;rsquo;d been amazed at the dedication Jobs and Wozniak must have had to work in a garage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those guys must have been freezing!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Right Kind of Stubborn</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/persistence/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-right-kind-of-stubborn&#34;&gt;The Right Kind of Stubborn&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Successful people tend to be persistent. New ideas often don&amp;rsquo;t work at first, but they&amp;rsquo;re not deterred. They keep trying and eventually find something that does.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mere obstinacy, on the other hand, is a recipe for failure. Obstinate people are so annoying. They won&amp;rsquo;t listen. They beat their heads against a wall and get nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But is there any real difference between these two cases? Are persistent and obstinate people actually behaving differently? Or are they doing the same thing, and we just label them later as persistent or obstinate depending on whether they turned out to be right or not?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Kinds of Judgement</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/judgement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/judgement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/judgement/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;two-kinds-of-judgement&#34;&gt;Two Kinds of Judgement&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2007&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two different ways people judge you. Sometimes judging you correctly is the end goal. But there&amp;rsquo;s a second much more common type of judgement where it isn&amp;rsquo;t. We tend to regard all judgements of us as the first type. We&amp;rsquo;d probably be happier if we realized which are and which aren&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first type of judgement, the type where judging you is the end goal, include court cases, grades in classes, and most competitions. Such judgements can of course be mistaken, but because the goal is to judge you correctly, there&amp;rsquo;s usually some kind of appeals process. If you feel you&amp;rsquo;ve been misjudged, you can protest that you&amp;rsquo;ve been treated unfairly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Doesn&#39;t Seem Like Work?</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/work/&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-doesnt-seem-like-work&#34;&gt;What Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Seem Like Work?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2015&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My father is a mathematician. For most of my childhood he worked for Westinghouse, modelling nuclear reactors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was one of those lucky people who know early on what they want to do. When you talk to him about his childhood, there&amp;rsquo;s a clear watershed at about age 12, when he &amp;ldquo;got interested in maths.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He grew up in the small Welsh seacoast town of Pwllheli. As we retraced his walk to school on Google Street View, he said that it had been nice growing up in the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What You&#39;ll Wish You&#39;d Known</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/hs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/hs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/hs/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-youll-wish-youd-known&#34;&gt;What You&amp;rsquo;ll Wish You&amp;rsquo;d Known&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(I wrote this talk for a high school. I never actually gave it, because the school authorities vetoed the plan to invite me.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I said I was speaking at a high school, my friends were curious. What will you say to high school students? So I asked them, what do you wish someone had told you in high school? Their answers were remarkably similar. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you what we all wish someone had told us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why It&#39;s Safe for Founders to Be Nice</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_en/safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/paul_graham/essays_zh/safe/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-its-safe-for-founders-to-be-nice&#34;&gt;Why It&amp;rsquo;s Safe for Founders to Be Nice&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2015&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently got an email from a founder that helped me understand something important: why it&amp;rsquo;s safe for startup founders to be nice people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I grew up with a cartoon idea of a very successful businessman (in the cartoon it was always a man): a rapacious, cigar-smoking, table-thumping guy in his fifties who wins by exercising power, and isn&amp;rsquo;t too fussy about how. As I&amp;rsquo;ve written before, one of the things that has surprised me most about startups is how few of the most successful founders are like that. Maybe successful people in other industries are; I don&amp;rsquo;t know; but not startup founders. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
