<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organization on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/organization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Organization on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 18:29:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On time management</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/on-time-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 18:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/on-time-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/zh/on-time-management.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/2008/08/07/on-time-management/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-time-management&#34;&gt;On time management&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prodded by several comments, I have finally decided to write up some my thoughts on time management here. I actually have been drafting something about this subject for a while, but I soon realised that my own experience with time management is still very much a work in progress (you should see my backlog of papers that need writing up) and I don’t yet have a coherent or definitive philosophy on this topic (other than my &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/career-advice/orig/on-writing/&#34;&gt;advice on writing papers&lt;/a&gt;, for instance my &lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/advice-on-writing-papers/write-a-rapid-prototype-first/&#34;&gt;page on rapid prototyping&lt;/a&gt;). Also, I can only talk about my own personal experiences, which probably do not generalise to all personality types or work situations, though perhaps readers may wish to contribute their own thoughts, experiences, or suggestions in the comments here. [I should also add that I don’t always follow my own advice on these matters, often to my own regret.]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write a rapid prototype first</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/en/write-a-rapid-prototype-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 09:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/en/write-a-rapid-prototype-first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/zh/write-a-rapid-prototype-first.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/advice-on-writing-papers/write-a-rapid-prototype-first/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;write-a-rapid-prototype-first&#34;&gt;Write a rapid prototype first&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The best performance improvement is the transition from the nonworking state to the working state.&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Ousterhout&#34;&gt;John Ousterhout&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discovering a solution to a mathematical problem is only half of the battle. Actually writing down the argument that you’ve discovered formally can also be a daunting task, especially if the argument is lengthy and is not modeled on an existing one in the literature. While every individual detail of the argument may be clear to the author, the overall structure of the argument may not be immediately obvious. In particular, it is often difficult to make the (important) decisions about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/en/organise-the-paper/&#34;&gt;organisation of the argument&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/writing-guide/en/use-good-notation/&#34;&gt;selection of good notation&lt;/a&gt;, until a large part of the paper is already written, at which point any changes in the organisation or in the notation often become painful to implement. (Many times in the past, I have started to write a paper without devoting enough thought to the overall structure, and spent a lot of time establishing some lemmas which I thought were important, only to realise later that one did not actually need the lemma, thus wasting quite a lot of time.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
