<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Expertise on Linguista</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1355/tags/expertise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Expertise on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1355/tags/expertise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus and Credibility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/cred/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/cred/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/cred/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;coronavirus-and-credibility&#34;&gt;Coronavirus and Credibility&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a video of TV journalists and politicians confidently saying that the coronavirus would be no worse than the flu. What struck me about it was not just how mistaken they seemed, but how daring. How could they feel safe saying such things?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The answer, I realized, is that they didn&amp;rsquo;t think they could get caught. They didn&amp;rsquo;t realize there was any danger in making false predictions. These people constantly make false predictions, and get away with it, because the things they make predictions about either have mushy enough outcomes that they can bluster their way out of trouble, or happen so far in the future that few remember what they said.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Be an Expert in a Changing World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/ecw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/ecw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/ecw/&#34;&gt;Chinese Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-be-an-expert-in-a-changing-world&#34;&gt;How to Be an Expert in a Changing World&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the world were static, we could have monotonically increasing confidence in our beliefs. The more (and more varied) experience a belief survived, the less likely it would be false. Most people implicitly believe something like this about their opinions. And they&amp;rsquo;re justified in doing so with opinions about things that don&amp;rsquo;t change much, like human nature. But you can&amp;rsquo;t trust your opinions in the same way about things that change, which could include practically everything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Do Great Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/greatwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/greatwork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/greatwork/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-do-great-work&#34;&gt;How to Do Great Work&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you collected lists of techniques for doing great work in a lot of different fields, what would the intersection look like? I decided to find out by making it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Partly my goal was to create a guide that could be used by someone working in any field. But I was also curious about the shape of the intersection. And one thing this exercise shows is that it does have a definite shape; it&amp;rsquo;s not just a point labelled &amp;ldquo;work hard.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
