<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory on Linguista</title>
    <link>https://linguage.github.io/tags/theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theory on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:49:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://linguage.github.io/tags/theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>There’s more to mathematics than grades and exams and methods</title>
      <link>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 18:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/orig/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linguage.github.io/terencetao/zh/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods.zh/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/career-advice/theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods/&#34;&gt;原博客链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;theres-more-to-mathematics-than-grades-and-exams-and-methods&#34;&gt;There’s more to mathematics than grades and exams and methods&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you have mastered numbers, you will in fact no longer be reading numbers, any more than you read words when reading books. You will be reading meanings.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(Harold Geneen, &amp;ldquo;Managing&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When learning mathematics as an undergraduate student, there is often a heavy emphasis on grade averages, and on exams which often emphasize memorisation of techniques and theory than on actual conceptual understanding, or on either intellectual or intuitive thought. There are good reasons for this; there is a certain amount of theory and technique that must be practiced before one can really get anywhere in mathematics (much as there is a certain amount of drill required before one can play a musical instrument well). It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how much innate mathematical talent and intuition you have; if you are unable to, say, compute a multidimensional integral, manipulate matrix equations, understand abstract definitions, or correctly set up a proof by induction, then it is unlikely that you will be able to work effectively with higher mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
