<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inequality on Linguista</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1355/tags/inequality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inequality on Linguista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1355/tags/inequality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How People Get Rich Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/richnow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/richnow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/richnow/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-people-get-rich-now&#34;&gt;How People Get Rich Now&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every year since 1982, Forbes magazine has published a list of the richest Americans. If we compare the 100 richest people in 1982 to the 100 richest in 2020, we notice some big differences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1982 the most common source of wealth was inheritance. Of the 100 richest people, 60 inherited from an ancestor. There were 10 du Pont heirs alone. By 2020 the number of heirs had been cut in half, accounting for only 27 of the biggest 100 fortunes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inequality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/inequality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/inequality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/inequality/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;inequality&#34;&gt;Inequality&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This essay is derived from a talk at Defcon 2005.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Suppose you wanted to get rid of economic inequality. There are two ways to do it: give money to the poor, or take it away from the rich. But they amount to the same thing, because if you want to give money to the poor, you have to get it from somewhere. You can&amp;rsquo;t get it from the poor, or they just end up where they started. You have to get it from the rich.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Gap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/gap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/gap/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;mind-the-gap&#34;&gt;Mind the Gap&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When people care enough about something to do it well, those who do it best tend to be far better than everyone else. There&amp;rsquo;s a huge gap between Leonardo and second-rate contemporaries like Borgognone. You see the same gap between Raymond Chandler and the average writer of detective novels. A top-ranked professional chess player could play ten thousand games against an ordinary club player without losing once.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Refragmentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/re/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_en/re/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;→ &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1355/paul_graham/essays_zh/re/&#34;&gt;中文版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-refragmentation&#34;&gt;The Refragmentation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2016&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One advantage of being old is that you can see change happen in your lifetime. A lot of the change I&amp;rsquo;ve seen is fragmentation. US politics is much more polarized than it used to be. Culturally we have ever less common ground. The creative class flocks to a handful of happy cities, abandoning the rest. And increasing economic inequality means the spread between rich and poor is growing too. I&amp;rsquo;d like to propose a hypothesis: that all these trends are instances of the same phenomenon. And moreover, that the cause is not some force that&amp;rsquo;s pulling us apart, but rather the erosion of forces that had been pushing us together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
